本字幕由志愿者义务贡献，采用许可协议
知识共享 署名-非商业性使用-相同方式共享 3.0 美国
Stanford University.
斯坦福大学
>> All right, well, welcome to Stanford CS193P,
欢迎参加 2017 年冬季学期斯坦福
that's Developing Applications for iOS, winter of 2017.
这是2017年冬季iOS的应用程序。
CS193P 课程，iOS 应用程序开发
CS193P课程,iOS应用程序开发
So today, our topic is to talk about custom views, okay,
今天我们要讲的是自定义视图，
specifically the drawing side of having custom views.
特别是有自定义视图的绘图方面。
And this is gonna be a more typical lecture than last
这是一个比上次更典型的讲座
time because I'll be doing some slides and
时间因为我要做一些幻灯片
explaining the concepts to you, and
向你解释这些概念
then I'll go into a demo that shows you how we do it all.
然后我将进入一个演示，向您展示我们是如何做到这一切的。
So what is a view?
那么什么是视图呢?
A view is a subclass of UIView,
视图是UIView的一个子类，
which is in UIKit in iOS.
在iOS的UIKit中。
And all it does is carve out or
它所做的只是雕刻或
represent a rectangular area on screen.
代表屏幕上的矩形区域。
And that rectangular area defines a coordinate space
这个矩形区域定义了一个坐标空间
that we're gonna draw in and that we're gonna get
我们要画出来，我们会得到
multi-touch events like pinches and
多点触控的事件，像掐和
swipes and all that stuff.
和所有这些东西。
So today,
所以今天,
I'm just gonna focus on the drawing side of that all and
我将把重点放在画的这一边
then we'll start talking about the gestures on Wednesday.
然后我们将在周三开始讨论这些手势。
So these views, these little rectangle areas
这些视图，这些小矩形区域
are put on screen in this hierarchical way.
以这种分层的方式呈现在屏幕上。
And that just means that the views have subviews
这意味着视图有子视图
inside of them.
在他们。
Now any given view can only have one superview,
现在任何给定的视图只能有一个超级视图，
that's the view that it's contained in.
这就是它所包含的观点。
But it can have any number of subviews,
但它可以有任意数量的子视图，
so views made out of it.
所以这些观点是由它产生的。
So for example, on the calculator, we had for
例如，在计算器上，我们有
example, stack view, okay.
例子中,堆栈视图。
It had a lot of subviews,
它有很多次视图，
all the buttons that we stacked in it.
我们堆在里面的所有按钮。
In fact, some of the stack views had other stack views as
实际上，一些堆栈视图有其他堆栈视图
their subviews.
他们的子视图。
And then those stack views had more subviews,
然后这些堆栈视图有更多的子视图，
which were buttons or whatever, okay.
这是按钮之类的。
So that's how we build our UI is this hierarchical
这就是我们构建UI的方式
collection of these rectangular areas.
这些矩形区域的集合。
Now, at the very, very, very top there's a special UIView
现在，在非常非常高的顶部有一个特殊的UIView
called UIWindow class, we don't deal with that in iOS.
在iOS中，我们不使用UIWindow类。
In fact, the only time you would ever do anything with
事实上，你唯一一次做任何事情的时候
the UIWindow is if you were building an app that maybe
UIWindow是如果你正在构建一个应用程序
projected to a projector.
将一个投影仪。
So that you had two screens, your device and
所以你有两个屏幕，你的设备和
then maybe some external projector or
然后可能是外部投影仪
something, then you might care about UIWindow.
有些东西，你可能关心的是UIWindow。
But otherwise, it's all about UIView, okay?
但除此之外，它都是关于UIView的?
All of our arrangement of the screen is all about how we
我们所有的屏幕布局都是关于我们如何
arrange the UIViews.
安排ui视图。
Now this hierarchy, okay, these rectangular areas inside
这个层级，好的，这些矩形区域
of rectangular areas, is almost always built
在矩形区域，几乎总是建立
in Interface Builder, inside Xcode, okay?
在接口生成器中，在Xcode中?
That's how we built the stack view stuff.
这就是我们构建堆栈视图的方式。
We dragged out a bunch of buttons and
我们拖出一串按钮
then we selected them and said,
然后我们选他们说，
"Embed in Stack View." Well, that wrapped it in there.
But we can also build that hierarchy by dragging views
但我们也可以通过拖动视图来构建层次结构
out of the utilities,
公用事业,
bottom of the utilities window there, inside other views.
在工具窗口的底部，在其他视图中。
So you can drag,
所以你可以拖拽,
do it by dragging-dropping inside of other views.
在其他视图中拖放。
It is possible to do it in code but
在代码中也可以这样做
usually we're doing it graphically.
通常我们用图形来做。
If you're doing it in code,
如果你在代码中做，
the two main methods involved in building and
两种主要的建筑方法
destroying this hierarchy, are addSubview, okay,
破坏这个层级，是addSubview，好的，
addSubview, takes a view as an argument.
addSubview，以一个视图作为参数。
You send it to the "soon-to-be" superview of that
你把它发送到“即将成为”的超级视图
In other words, you ask another view,
换句话说，你问另一个观点，
view.
视图。
please add this other view as subview of yourself.
请添加另一个视图作为您自己的子视图。
Now when you're doing the opposite, taking some view out
现在当你做相反的事情时，要考虑一下
of the hierarchy, you don't send it to the superview.
在层次结构中，您不会将它发送到superview。
You send it to the actual view itself,
你将它发送到实际视图本身，
basically remove yourself from this view hierarchy.
从这个视图层级中删除自己。
So you send removeFromSuperview
所以你发送removeFromSuperview
to the actual view you want removed.
你想要删除的实际视图。
Now where does this hierarchy start?
那么这个层次结构是从哪里开始的呢?
I guess you could say it starts in UIWindow.
我猜你可以说它是从UIWindow开始的。
But for our purposes, we don't even pay attention to that.
但出于我们的目的，我们甚至没有注意到这一点。
It starts at the top level view
它从顶层视图开始
in that scene in Interface Builder.
在界面构建器的那个场景中。
The scene that's controlled by our view controller, right?
这个场景由我们的视图控制器控制，对吧?
That rectangular area that we work in.
我们在这个矩形区域工作。
There's a top,
有一个,
top level view that covers the whole space up there.
顶层视图覆盖了整个空间。
And there is an important instance variable,
有一个重要的实例变量，
property, in UIViewController.
属性,在ui中。
Okay, so all subclasses of UIViewController get
所有UIViewController的子类都得到
this property.
这个性质。
It's called view and it's a UIView and a top level view.
它叫view，它是UIView和顶层视图。
And it's very important to understand that in an MVC,
在MVC中，理解这一点很重要，
the controller has this, always has this var which
控制器有这个，总是有这个var
points to the very top of that view hierarchy in its scene.
在它的场景中，指向视图层级的最顶端。
This top level view is important because for example,
顶层视图很重要，例如，
when you rotate, it's the thing whose bounds changes,
当你旋转时，它的边界会改变，
that top level view.
顶级视图。
And you're gonna learn a little later that when
稍后你会学到这个
the bounds of a view changes, there's a mechanism for
视图的边界变化，有一个机制
offering all of its subviews an opportunity to change.
提供所有的子视图一个改变的机会。
So that's why when we rotate device,
这就是为什么当我们旋转设备时，
that top level view changes from being tall and
顶层视图从高到高
thin to being wide and less tall.
瘦到宽，不高。
And that causes all those stack views and
这导致了所有这些堆栈视图
everything else to start getting resized as well,
其他的东西也开始调整大小，
because they're all subviews of this top level view, okay?
因为它们都是顶层视图的子视图?
If you were going to add views to the view hierarchy
如果您要向视图层次结构添加视图
programmatically rather than dragging and
编程而不是拖拽
dropping them, then you would need this view because it's
去掉它们，你就需要这个视图，因为它是
the top of the entire view hierarchy.
整个视图层次结构的顶部。
And you would kinda work your way down
你会慢慢的往下走
to find out where you want to put that view.
要知道你想把这个观点放在哪里。
But we don't otherwise actually look at this view
但实际上我们并没有看这个视图
much because we usually have outlets, rights?
因为我们通常有销售点和权利?
IBOutlets--like the display that points to the label--that
iboutlet，比如指向标签的显示
gives us access to that label.
让我们接触到那个标签。
That's all we want, so
这就是我们想要的
we don't have to go looking at the top level view and
我们不需要看顶层视图
looking all down the views, okay?
看看所有的视图，明白吗?
So this is important to know about but
这一点很重要
surprisingly you don't access it that much, okay.
令人惊讶的是，你并没有那么多地访问它。
This view is automatically hooked up for you in
这个视图会自动为你连接起来
Interface Builder when you drag out a View Controller.
拖出视图控制器时的接口生成器。
It's just all magically hooked up,
它只是神奇地连接起来，
you don't have to worry about that.
你不必为此担心。
Okay, let's talk about initialization of the UIView.
好，我们来讨论UIView的初始化。
As usual, when you saw the lecture from last time,
像往常一样，当你上次看到讲座的时候，
you probably realize, whoa, initialization has a lot of
你可能会意识到，初始化有很多
caveats when you're talking about initializing a class,
注意，当你在讨论初始化一个类时，
Remember all those rules I was going through?
记得我所经历的那些规则吗?
right?
对吧?
Required convenience and its inheritance, all this stuff.
需要方便和继承，所有这些东西。
So we try to avoid initializers generally as much
所以我们尽量避免初始化
as we can by doing all the things I talked
就像我们可以做所有我说过的事情一样
about on Wednesday, like setting things equal or
在周三的时候，就像把东西放在一起一样
even using lazy or something like that.
即使是懒惰或类似的东西。
But if you can't avoid it,
但如果你无法避免，
UIView has an interesting initializer situation.
UIView有一个有趣的初始化程序。
It has two initializers that you have to deal with.
它有两个初始化器，你必须处理。
Okay, one of them, init, with the frame is the argument, is
好的，其中一个，init，和框架是参数，是
the one that you would call if you're trying to create a view
如果你想创建一个视图，你会调用它
in code, which you'll probably never do in this class, okay?
在代码中，在这个类中你可能永远都不会做，明白吗?
Because you're always gonna use or
因为你总是要用或者
do it in Interface Builder with Xcode.
使用Xcode在接口构建器中进行操作。
But, so that's the kind of in-code one.
但是，这是一种内部编码。
And init with this coder thing,
然后用这个编码来初始化，
which I'll talk about right at the end of class,
我将在课结束时讲到，
but it's not important to know early on.
但早期了解并不重要。
That's the init that gets called when your stuff come
这是当你的东西来的时候被调用的init
outs of Interface Builder, right?
接口生成器的失效，对吗?
When it comes from, when you built in Xcode.
当它来自于，当你在Xcode中构建的时候。
All the stuff that you're building in Interface Builder
你在接口构建器中构建的所有东西
essentially gets coded,
基本上被编码,
that's what this coder business is about.
这就是编码器业务的内容。
Gets coded into an XML file, kind of freeze dried.
被编码成一个XML文件，一种冷冻干燥。
And then when you run your program, that XML file gets
运行程序时，XML文件就会得到
loaded in and it's kind of the instructions for
加载进来，这是一种指令
how to create all those objects, okay?
如何创建所有这些对象?
And init with coder is the initializer it uses
与编码器的init是它使用的初始化器
to recreate the view.
重新创建视图。
So if you have any code that needs to go in an initializer,
如果你有一个初始化器需要的代码，
like you need to initialize some var in your UIView,
你需要在UIView中初始化一些var，
you have to do it like this.
你必须这样做。
Override both of these inits,
重写这两个inits，
one of them is a required init, the coder one.
其中一个是必需的init，编码器。
And we create some other method like this green setup
我们还创建了一些其他的方法，比如绿色设置
method I have.
我有方法。
And just call that method from both of them.
把这个方法从它们两个中调用。
That way you're guaranteed that whether your custom view
这样你就可以保证你的自定义视图
is created in code or created in Interface Builder,
是在代码中创建的，或者是在接口构建器中创建的，
it will get initialized properly.
它会得到适当的初始化。
If you have vars that have to be initialized, you may not be
如果您有必须初始化的vars，您可能没有
able to use this mechanism of course because you can't
当然可以使用这个机制，因为你不能
call methods in yourself until you're initialized.
调用方法，直到初始化。
So you might have to have that var initialization be
所以你可能需要进行var初始化
somewhat duplicated there.
有些重复。
There's another alternative to initialization though and this
这是另一个初始化的替代方法
is for any other object that comes out of Interface Builder
对于任何来自接口构建器的对象
which is called awakeFromNib.
被称为awakeFromNib。
Okay, awakeFromNib.
好的,awakeFromNib。
This is sent to every single object that ever comes out
这被发送到每一个被输出的对象
of Interface Builder file, okay, that you edit
接口生成器文件，好的，你编辑
in the story board there including views and
在故事板中，包括视图和
your View Controller for that matter.
你的视图控制器。
And so
所以
the "Your object must be completely initialized."
“您的对象必须完全初始化。”
Those restrictions are not satisfied by this.
这些限制并不满足于此。
But still you can put code in there, you get, get going.
但是你仍然可以把代码放在那里，你得到，开始。
And we're gonna learn all kinds of ways to do
我们要学习各种方法
initialization throughout our system down the road,
在整个系统的初始化过程中，
but that's basically how you initialize UIViews.
这就是初始化uiview的方法。
Okay so we're gonna talk now about UIView
现在我们要讨论UIView
as this rectangular area in which we're gonna draw.
这是我们要画的矩形面积。
And so to do that we need talk about some types.
为了做到这一点，我们需要讨论一些类型。
They're some very important types that you need to know.
他们是一些你需要知道的非常重要的类型。
One of them is CGFloat.
其中一个是CGFloat。
So CGFloat is a floating point value.
所以CGFloat是一个浮点值。
All of your coordinates that you're gonna be drawing in
你要画的所有坐标
are all floating point values, but they're not doubles,
都是浮点值，但它们不是双打，
they're not floats, they're CGFloats.
它们不是浮点值，而是cgfloat。
So this is a type,
这是一种类型，
a real type that you have to use all the time
一个你必须一直使用的真实类型
when you're doing anything with the drawing, okay?
当你用画图做任何事的时候?
CG stands for Core Graphics,
CG代表核心图形，
this is the "graphics float" right here, okay?
这就是"图形浮动"
There's also a CGPoint which is just a struct with two
还有一个CGPoint，就是一个有两个的struct
things in it, x and y, they're both CGFloats, CGPoint
里面的东西，x和y，它们都是cgfloat,CGPoint
represents a point in your coordinate system somewhere.
表示坐标系中的一个点。
Again, floating point coordinates.
再次,浮点坐标。
There's also CGSize, which represents an extent.
也有CGSize，代表一定程度。
You know, a width and a height, okay?
宽度和高度?
Only, it's just the struct, with two CGFloats, width and
只有结构，有两个cgfloat，宽度和
height, simple.
高度,简单。
And there's CGRect, of course, which is a rectangle.
这是CGRect，当然，这是一个矩形。
It's a struct that has an origin, which is CGPoint, and
它是一个有原点的结构，也就是CGPoint
an extent, which is a size.
一个范围，一个大小。
So a rectangle represents a size, okay?
一个矩形代表一个大小，对吧?
So creating a CGRect--there's actually quite a few
创建一个CGRect，实际上有很多
initializers for it.
初始值设定项。
You can create an origin and size,
你可以创建一个原点和大小，
you can do an x y with height, things like that.
你可以做一个有高度的x y，像这样。
And CGRect also has a lot of really cool,
CGRect也很酷，
little convenience vars and funcs and thing like that.
几乎没有方便的vars和功能。
maxY, midY, those'll tell you thing like where's the left
maxY,midY，这些会告诉你什么是左边
Like minX,
喜欢风骚女子,
edge of your rect to the top to the left or the bottom.
在你的矩形的边缘到左上方或底部。
The middle points, etc.
中间点,等等。
There's also nice functions like intersects other rect
还有一些很好的函数，比如与其它矩形相交
will return whether the two rectangles cross over.
将返回两个矩形是否交叉。
And there's even contains whether a point
甚至还有一个点
is inside the rectangle, etc.
在矩形内，等等。
So there's quite a few of these.
有很多这样的例子。
I can't put them all on the slide, so
我不能把它们都放在幻灯片上
you're gonna wanna familiarize yourselves with CGRect.
你们要熟悉CGRect。
Because it probably has a lot of things in there that
因为它可能有很多东西
you would otherwise be writing your own code to do.
否则，您将编写自己的代码。
Okay, so now that we have those types,
好的，现在我们有了这些类型，
those four types, we can start talking about this coordinate
这四种类型，我们可以开始讨论这个坐标
system that we're gonna be doing our drawing in.
我们要画的系统。
Now, the most important thing to understand,
现在，最重要的是，
the simplest thing, is that the origin of this coordinate
最简单的就是这个坐标的原点
system is in the upper left of the screen.
系统在屏幕的左上角。
It's not Cartesian coordinates which the origin would be in
它不是笛卡尔坐标，原点在这里
the lower left of the screen because in Cartesian
屏幕左下方，因为在笛卡尔
coordinates increasing y means up, but
坐标增加y表示向上，但是
in this coordinate system increasing y means going down,
在这个坐标系中y表示向下，
down the screen, okay?
屏幕上,好吗?
So very important to understand that.
理解这点非常重要。
So you can see that point I have up there, 500,35 that's
可以看到这里有个点，500 35
500 over and 35 down from the origin upper left, okay?
Now, the units in here that we're drawing are points.
现在，我们画的单位是点。
Okay, be very careful that you understand the unit
好，非常小心，你理解这个单位
terminology here, okay?
术语在这里,好吗?
It's in points, not pixels.
它是点，不是像素。
A pixel is like the smallest possible little light
一个像素就像最小的可能的小光
that can be turned on on your screen.
可以在屏幕上打开。
Okay, now some devices have a lot of pixels
现在有些设备有很多像素
per point--they're very dense.
每点——它们非常密集。
And that's really great, because if you're drawing
这很好，因为如果你画
smooth curves--like fonts are just
平滑曲线——就像字体一样
smooth curves being drawn--you don't get jaggy edges,
光滑曲线画出来，没有棱角，
because there's so many tiny little points, okay?
因为有这么多微小的点?
But we can't make it, so that we draw in the pixel space,
但是我们做不到，我们画出像素空间，
otherwise, on a very dense pixel screen,
否则，在一个非常密集的像素屏幕上，
our image would be really small.
我们的图像会很小。
And then, in an undense one, it'd be really big,
然后，在一个不稠密的地方，它会非常大，
because the pixels are really big.
因为像素非常大。
So we instead of drawing in pixels,
我们不画出像素，
we draw in points, okay?
我们画点，好吗?
This is the same point by the way that is like the point
这和点的情况是一样的
size of a font.
字体的大小。
A 12 point font, same word there, same point, okay?
一个12点的字体，同一个词，相同的点?
So, you can find out though how many pixels there are per
所以，你可以找出每个像素有多少像素
point, in other words how high resolution your screen is,
换句话说，屏幕分辨率有多高，
with this var in UIView called contentScaleFactor.
在UIView中，这个var被称为contentScaleFactor。
It's a CGFloat, it's either gonna be one, two, or
它是一个CGFloat，要么是1，要么是2
three currently.
三个目前。
Like, the iPhone 7 Plus is three.
比如，iPhone 7 Plus是3。
Three pixels per point in each direction.
每个方向有三个像素。
And the older like iPhone 4s maybe?
而像iPhone 4s这样的老旧的可能吗?
Maybe all the way back to the 4 would be one.
也许一直到4是1。
Okay, some of the older iPads would be one.
好的，一些旧的ipad会是一个。
The newer iPads would be two.
新款ipad将是两款。
So, If you're doing anything where you have to pay
所以，如果你在做任何你必须支付的事情
Okay?
明白吗?
attention to the number of pixels of points,
注意点的像素个数，
this is what you need.
这是你需要的。
Now the great thing is, most of the time you don't care
现在最重要的是，大部分时间你都不在乎
because when you're using iOS to draw with a font,
因为当你用iOS来绘制字体时，
it's automatically gonna do super smooth turns, and
它会自动进行非常平滑的旋转
you don't even have to know what the scale factor is.
你甚至不需要知道比例因子是什么。
Even if you're just drawing an arc,
即使你画了一条弧线，
it'll make sure you do as little jaggies as possible.
它会确保你尽可能地做小的锯齿。
So, you rarely have to know this.
所以，你很少需要知道这些。
But actually, wake up.
但实际上,醒来。
You do need to know for assignment three, okay?
你们需要知道作业3，对吧?
So assignment three, you will have to know this.
第三个作业，你们必须知道这个。
Alright, now.
好了,现在。
The most important var in all of UIView is this one: bounds.
所有UIView中最重要的var是这个:界限。
And even in that really important var,
即使在这个非常重要的var中，
really what you care about is the size.
你真正关心的是尺寸。
This is, in your drawing coordinate system,
这是，在你的绘图坐标系中，
the space you have to draw in.
你要画的空间。
This is basically the size of your view in your own drawing
这基本上是你自己画的尺寸
coordinate system.
坐标系统。
So any time you're doing any drawing and
所以任何时候你画的时候
you wanna draw something that's as wide as your view,
你想要画出和你的观点一样宽的东西，
you're gonna use bounds.size.width here.
你会使用bounds.size。宽度。
And you're almost always gonna have your bounds' origin be
你几乎总是能得到积分限
(0, 0) so if you want put something in upper left you're
gonna put it at (0, 0) or close to (0, 0).
把它放到(0,0)或者接近(0,0)
So this rect, bounds,
这个矩形边界,
is describing the area have to draw in.
描述这个区域必须画进去。
Now it's important because you obviously want to,
这很重要，因为你显然想，
depending on your size, draw yourself appropriately.
根据你的尺寸，适当地画自己。
And it's also important because there are two other
这也很重要，因为还有另外两个
vars that often get confused by students with bounds, and
那些经常被学生们搞糊涂的vars
which are quite different: that is frame and center.
这是完全不同的:那是框架和中心。
So frame and center have nothing to do
所以框架和中心没有什么可做的
with where you're drawing, that's bounds.
在你画的地方，这是界限。
Frame and center is where you are in your super view.
框架和中心是你在你的超级视图中的位置。
So here's a picture of that frame and center.
这是那个框架和中心的图片。
So center is where your center is in your superview's
中心是你的中心在你的超级视图中
coordinate system and frame is a rectangle that completely
坐标系和坐标系是一个完全的矩形
encases you in your superview's coordinate system.
在你的超级视图的坐标系统中包围你。
And you might think, well the size of my frame is gonna be
你可能会想，我的坐标系的大小是
exactly the same size as my bounds size, right?
和我的边界大小完全一样，对吧?
And the answer is no, because views can be rotated.
答案是否定的，因为视图可以旋转。
And if you have ever rotated a view like this green one,
如果你曾经旋转过这样一个绿色的视图，
Inside the code that's drawing in View B, its bounds just
在视图B中绘制的代码中，它的边界
View B.
视图B。
looks like a normal rectangle, the fact that it's rotated,
看起来像一个普通的矩形，它旋转的事实，
it doesn't even know it's rotated.
它甚至不知道它在旋转。
But if you look at the center of it, or if you look at
但如果你看它的中心，或者你看
the frame that encloses it, look, it's not the same size.
包围它的框架，看，它的大小不一样。
It has to be bigger because, to the superview, View A,
它必须更大，因为，对于父视图，视图A，
It's bigger.
它是大的。
View B kinda looks like a diamond, right?
B看起来有点像钻石，对吧?
So it has to be bigger.
所以它必须更大。
So the bottom line here, never use frame or center to draw.
所以底线是，不要用框架或中心来画。
Frame and center are only used to position you
框架和中心只用于定位你
in your super view.
在你的父视图。
Okay, you can use either one.
你可以用任意一个。
If you set the center, it'll move the frame,
如果你设置中心，它会移动这个坐标系，
if you set the frame, it'll adjust the center, okay.
如果你设置框架，它会调整中心。
They're tied together.
他们绑在一起。
Okay.
好吧。
How do we create views?
我们如何创建视图?
Okay, because I already told you we don't really use
好吧，因为我已经告诉过你我们不用
the initializer, we don't, you know,
初始化器，我们不，你知道，
create them in code very much.
在代码中创建它们。
What we usually do is we drag them out
我们通常做的就是把它们拖出来
Okay?
明白吗?
from the Object Palette in the bottom of the utilities window
从工具窗口底部的对象面板中
in Interface Builder.
在界面构建器。
But if I built a custom view, Paul's view or
但如果我建立一个自定义视图，保罗的视图
something, it's not going to be in the palette, okay.
一些东西，它不会在调色板里，好的。
Xcode didn't ship with my view in the palette.
Xcode没有将我的视图发送到调色板中。
So instead, there's a generic view, just plain UIView, and
相反，这里有一个泛型视图，只是普通的UIView
you're gonna drag that in.
你要把它拖进来。
But then, you're gonna inspect it using the top half of
然后，你要用上半部分来检查它
the utilities pane on the right, right?
右边的工具面板，对吗?
You're gonna inspect it and
你要检查它
change its class to not be UIView.
改变它的类不为UIView。
It's gonna be your subclass of UIView, so Paul view or
它将是UIView的子类，所以是Paul view
whatever, okay?
无论如何,好吗?
And this is a very important step to remember.
这是一个非常重要的步骤。
When you create a custom view and you drag it into your UI,
创建自定义视图并将其拖放到UI中，
you have to change its class to be your custom class.
您必须将它的类更改为自定义类。
And we'll see that in the demo, how it works.
我们会在演示中看到它是如何工作的。
When you create it in code, of course,
当然，当你在代码中创建它的时候，
you're just doing UIView(frame:),
你只是做UIView(框架:)
and you provide the frame, okay?
你提供框架，明白吗?
And that frame, remember, what does it describe?
那个坐标系，记住，它描述了什么?
Describes where this view is gonna be in its super view
描述这个视图在它的超级视图中的位置
when it gets added, that's all the frame is doing, okay?
当它被添加时，这就是所有框架的作用?
And you can create it with UIView(), no arguments.
你可以用UIView()创建它，没有参数。
Then it will be zero width, zero height, and
然后它将是零宽，零高度
it'll be at zero, zero, so you won't even see it, so.
它在0处，所以你甚至看不到它。
But you could come along later and
但你可以晚点再来
change its frame and/or its center to move it around.
改变它的框架和/或它的中心来移动它。
Here, it's a really quick example,
这是一个非常简单的例子，
how to create a view in code.
如何在代码中创建视图。
I'm gonna create a UILabel.
我要创建一个UILabel。
UILabel is just a subclass of UIView.
UILabel只是UIView的一个子类。
And notice that on the second line there,
注意到，在第二行，
I'm just saying label = UILabel(frame:) of whatever.
我只是说标签= UILabel(frame:)。
So I'm giving it this frame, 20, 20, 150, right?
我给它这个坐标系，20,20,150，对吧?
And then I'm setting the text to "Hello".
然后我将文本设置为“Hello”。
Well, if I was doing this code in a UIViewController,
如果我在UIViewController中做这个代码，
then I could put it at that top level view,
然后我可以把它放到顶层视图，
it'd look like that, view.addSubview, okay?
它看起来是这样的，视图。addSubview,好吗?
And it would add the subview.
它会添加子视图。
Custom views, so why do I ever need a custom view?
自定义视图，为什么我需要一个自定义视图?
Either I need to do custom drawing or
我需要做自定义绘图
I need to do custom multi-touch input, okay?
我需要定制多点触摸输入，好吗?
Those are the reasons
这些都是原因
that you're gonna create a custom view.
你要创建一个自定义视图。
And so we're gonna focus on the drawing, and
所以我们要把重点放在绘图上
the drawing is very, very simple, okay?
这幅图非常非常简单，对吧?
There's this one method that's called draw.
有一种叫draw的方法。
And it takes one argument, which is a rect.
它需要一个参数，这是一个rect。
For historical reasons, we sometimes call it drawrect,
由于历史原因，我们有时称它为drawrect，
but it's not actually called drawrect anymore.
但实际上它不再被称为drawrect。
It's called draw, and the argument is called rect.
它叫做draw，这个论证叫做rect。
And this draw is gonna be sent to you by the system.
这个绘图会被系统发送给你。
It's sent to your UIView subclass,
它被发送到UIView子类，
you override it, and it gets sent to you by the system when
你重写它，它会被系统发送给你
the system wants you to draw yourself.
系统需要你自己画。
This is the only way you can draw in your view,
这是唯一能吸引你的方法，
is to be asked by the system to draw.
是由系统要求绘制的。
There is no other way to draw in iOS.
在iOS中没有其他的方法。
So what's that rectangle about?
这个矩形是关于什么的?
That rectangle is some sub-area in your bounds
这个长方形是积分范围内的子区域
that it wants you to draw.
它希望你画出来。
Now, that's a performance enhancement, because you can
这是一个性能增强，因为你可以
ignore that and draw your whole view, if you'd like.
如果你愿意的话，忽略它并画出你的整个视图。
But like in your assignment three, you're probably gonna
但就像你的作业3，你可能会
wanna pay attention to this rectangle because
想要注意这个矩形，因为
your assignment three's draw is gonna be pretty expensive,
你的作业3的画很贵，
so you wanna draw as little as possible.
你想画得越少越好。
So that's what this draw is, very simple,
这就是它的作用，非常简单，
it's just called by the system, time for you to draw.
它是由系统调用的，时间让你画。
It's the only way to draw.
这是唯一的方法。
So it's really, really easy to understand.
所以很容易理解。
Never call this method, ever.
永远不要调用这个方法。
If you ever call this method, it's wrong.
如果你调用这个方法，那就错了。
The system calls this method,
系统调用这个方法，
the system's the only one who calls this method.
系统是唯一调用此方法的系统。
So what happens if you need to draw?
如果你需要画画会怎样?
Something changed, and you wanna redraw.
有些东西变了，你想重新画。
You call one of these two methods, setNeedsDisplay or
您可以调用这两种方法之一，setNeedsDisplay或
setNeedsDisplay with the argument of a rect.
用rect的参数来显示setNeedsDisplay。
And that's telling the system, hey, system,
这告诉系统，嘿，系统，
my view needs to be redrawn.
我的观点需要重新考虑。
Please ask me to redraw it.
请让我重新画一下。
And at some appropriate time in the future,
在未来的适当时间，
it will ask you to redraw it.
它会要求你重新绘制它。
But it knows better than you when the best time to draw is,
但它比你知道的最好的时候，
believe me.
相信我。
And the rect that you can pass, that's just the rect
你可以通过的矩形，也就是rect
that's gonna be passed onto your draw.
那将会被传递到你的画图上。
So setNeedsDisplay with a rect is like an optimized
因此setNeedsDisplay与rect类似于优化
setNeedsDisplay.
setNeedsDisplay。
It's like, I need to be redrawn, but
就像，我需要重新画，但是
only this part of me.
只有这一部分。
And you can send this to any UIView, say, redraw this view.
你可以将它发送到任何UIView，比如说，重画这个视图。
Usually, views send it to themselves though because
通常，视图会自动发送给自己，因为
they're the ones who know best when they need to be redrawn,
当他们需要重新绘制时，他们才是最清楚的，
okay?
好吧?
Alright.
好吧。
So, how do I implement this drawrect,
那么，如何实现这个drawrect，
draw, draw with a CGRect argument guy?
画，画一个CGRect参数的人?
And the answer is, you're gonna do it with paths.
答案是，你要用路径来做。
You're gonna create paths, and then you're going to stroke
你要创造路径，然后你就会中风
them and fill them to make shapes and things like that.
把它们填满，做成形状之类的。
And then you're also gonna use text and images.
然后你还会使用文本和图像。
So that's the primary way that you're going to draw
这就是你们要画的主要方法
in there, okay?
在那里,好吗?
So we'll talk about text and images in a minute.
我们一会儿会讲到文本和图像。
Let's talk about the drawing with the paths first.
我们先来讨论一下路径图。
There's really two ways to do it.
有两种方法。
One is, you can get what's called a context,
一个是，你可以得到所谓的上下文，
a drawing context, and I'll show you how to get it.
一个绘图上下文，我将告诉您如何获得它。
And then you can send messages to that context like, move to
然后你可以把消息发送到这样的情境，比如，移动到
this point, draw a line to here, add an arc over here,
这一点，在这里画一条线，在这里加一条弧，
put some text over here, things like that, okay?
在这里输入一些文本，诸如此类，好吗?
Actually, the text we're gonna do in a different way,
实际上，我们要用另一种方式来写，
but, so that's one way.
这是一种方法。
And then the other way is, you can create a path object,
另一种方法是，你可以创建一个路径对象，
okay, using UIBezierPath, and it's the same kind of thing.
好的，使用UIBezierPath，它是一样的东西。
But you're gonna create this object that you're gonna tell
但你要创建这个对象
that object, okay, I want this path to be moving to here, and
这个对象，我想要这个路径移动到这里，然后
then a line here, and then an arc over to here, okay?
然后在这里画一条线，然后在这里画一条弧，对吧?
So you create this path, and
所以你创建了这个路径
then you send a message to that path saying, okay,
然后你向那条路径发送一条消息说，好吧，
stroke it.
中风。
So it's a subtle difference, but you'll see.
所以这是一个细微的区别，但你会看到。
We're gonna focus mainly on the UIBezierPath way,
我们主要关注UIBezierPath，
because it's kind of a little simpler.
因为它有点简单。
So let's understand the concepts here of
让我们来理解一下这里的概念
Core Graphics, that's what the CG is that you're seeing in
核心图形，这就是你看到的CG
all the places here.
这里所有的地方。
And the number one thing about Core Graphics is,
核心图形的第一件事是，
we need a context.
我们需要一个上下文。
And that context might be a drawing context for on-screen,
这个上下文可能是屏幕上的绘图上下文，
it might be a printing context if we're printing,
如果我们在印刷，它可能是一个印刷环境，
might be a context of drawing to an off-screen bitmap, etc.
可能是绘制到屏幕外的位图的上下文。
The one you care about is obviously the context to
你关心的那一个显然是背景
draw in your drawrect.
画在你的绘制矩形。
And you get that by calling this function.
通过调用这个函数得到这个。
This is just a Swift function,
这只是一个快速函数，
it's not on a class or anything.
它不是在一个类或任何东西上。
UIGraphicsGetCurrentContext(), and
UIGraphicsGetCurrentContext()和
that's going to get you a context that you can then
这将给你带来一个你可以了解的背景
tell it to create a path by moving and all that stuff.
告诉它通过移动和所有这些东西来创建一条路径。
Which is what you do then, you create these paths out of
这就是你所做的，你创造出这些路径
lines and arcs and things like that.
线条和弧线之类的东西。
Then you set drawing attributes in the context,
然后在context中设置绘图属性，
like the colors you wanna use, the fonts if you're doing
和你想要的颜色一样，字体如果你在做
text, line widths, those kinds of things.
文本，线宽，等等。
You set those all up, and then you stroke and fill.
你把这些都设置好了，然后你就可以了。
And that's it, stroking and
就是这样，抚摸和
filling are actually the only two directives that actually
实际上，填充实际上是两个指令
cause something to happen on screen.
在屏幕上发生一些事情。
But keep in mind that, like,
但请记住，
a font is basically just a really exquisite path filled,
字体基本上是一条非常精致的路径，
okay, or stroked and filled.
好的，或者是抚摸和填充。
So you can do a lot with stroking and filling.
所以你可以用抚摸和填充来做很多事情。
So UIBezierPath kinda encapsulates all of those
UIBezierPath把这些都封装起来了
Core Graphics concepts into an object.
将核心图形概念放入对象中。
And so I have an example here to show you how I would use
我举一个例子来说明我将如何使用
UIBezierPath to draw a triangle on screen.
UIBezierPath在屏幕上画一个三角形。
First, I'm gonna create the path by just saying,
首先，我要创建一条路径，
path = UIBezierPath().
路径= UIBezierPath()。
There are other initializers for it,
还有其他的初始化器，
which we'll see in the demo.
我们将在演示中看到。
But this one just creates a blank path to start.
但这个只是创建了一个空白的路径。
Then, you move around with the path.
然后，你沿着路径移动。
So like I can say, move to, which (80,
就像我说的，移动到，(80，
50) is like halfway across this, this little screen.
This is small screen, let's say, 160 points wide.
这是小屏幕，比如160个点。
80 and then 50 down, okay?
Then I'm gonna add a line down to 140, 50, see that, okay?
然后往下添加一行到140 50，看这个，好吗?
Then I'm gonna add another line over to 10,
然后再加一行到10，
off to the left, I'm still 150 down.
在左边，我还是150。
Then I'm gonna close the path, okay, using close, and
然后我要关闭路径，使用close，和
that just closes it back to the start.
这只是让它回到开始。
So look, I made a triangle, okay, really easy.
看，我做了一个三角形，很简单。
Now, the only thing is, all this code right here would
现在，唯一的问题是，所有这些代码都会
actually draw, instead of that triangle right there,
实际上画出来，而不是这个三角形，
would draw this: nothing.
会画出来:没有。
You would see no drawing with that code because we haven't
你不会看到这段代码，因为我们没有
stroked or filled it.
抚摸或填充它。
The stroking and filling is what draws.
抚摸和填充是吸引人的地方。
So how do we do the stroking and fill?
那么我们怎么做抚摸和填充呢?
Well, we need to set the colors that we wanna fill and
我们需要设置我们想要填充的颜色
stroke with.
中风。
But here, I'm taking green and
但在这里，我选择绿色
sending it the message setFill.
发送消息setFill。
So you actually set your color to fill with
所以你实际上设置了颜色来填充
by sending a message to a color.
通过发送一个消息到一个颜色。
You get a color, and you send it a message,
你得到一个颜色，然后发送一条消息，
set that as my fill color.
把它设为我的填充色。
And the same thing with a stroke,
中风也是一样，
set it as a stroke color.
把它设置为笔画颜色。
So I set my stroke color to red, my fill color to green.
所以我将笔画颜色设置为红色，填充颜色为绿色。
But when I'm talking about attributes like line width,
但是当我说到像线宽这样的属性时，
I send that to the path, to the UIBezierPath.
我将它发送到路径，到UIBezierPath。
Set your line width to three, okay, so I do that.
把线宽设为3，好，我这样做。
Now, if I say path.fill, now I get a green triangle.
现在，如果我说路径。填充，现在我得到一个绿色的三角形。
Because my fill color was green,
因为我的填充色是绿色的，
and it takes that path and it fills it in.
它走了那条路，把它填满了。
That's what fill does.
这是什么填满。
And similarly, if I say path.stroke,
类似地，如果我说路径，中风，
I get a red line around.
我得到一条红线。
Because the path that I took to get around there gets
因为我所走的道路是这样的
stroked with a three-point wide red line.
用三分宽的红线擦边。
So that's it, that's quite simple actually.
这很简单。
That's how we draw.
这就是我们画画。
And, UIBezierPath also knows how to draw a lot of common
UIBezierPath也知道如何画很多相同的东西
Okay?
明白吗?
shapes, like rounded rectangles, and ovals, and
形状，像圆角矩形和椭圆形
things like that, so you should familiarize yourself
诸如此类的事情，你应该熟悉一下自己
with UIBezierPath's API, of course.
当然，使用UIBezierPath的API。
Another cool thing you can do with UIBezierPath is you
你可以用UIBezierPath做的另一件很酷的事情是你
create a path like that triangle, and
创建一个类似三角形的路径
you can clip all your drawings to that path.
你可以把你所有的图画都夹在那条小路上。
So you could draw this elaborate picture that only
你可以画出这个复杂的图
show the part that shows through that triangle,
展示这个三角形的部分，
if you take that triangle path that we just created and
如果你取我们刚刚创建的三角形路径
say add clip to it.
添加剪辑到它。
Because after that,
因为在那之后,
all drawing is only gonna show up inside that triangle,
所有的图只会出现在三角形内，
you can make some pretty cool effects by doing it.
你可以做一些很酷的效果。
which is kinda cool,
这是有点酷,
The UIBezierPath also knows how to,
UIBezierPath也知道怎么做，
it has this method contains that will,
它有这个方法，
tell you whether a point is inside the path.
告诉你一个点是否在路径内。
So that's good if you want to do some touch thing or people
这很好，如果你想做一些接触的事情或人
are touching on something and you wanna do hit detection,
涉及到一些东西你想做的是检测，
basically, what they're touching on.
基本上，他们在触摸什么。
All right, and there's tons of other stuff in UIBezierPath,
在UIBezierPath里有很多其他的东西，
don't have time to cover it, you should look it up.
没有时间盖它，你应该查一下。
Okay, UIColor.
好的,用户界面颜色。
So UIColor, really simple.
所以用户界面颜色,很简单的。
Okay, there's some common colors like green, red,
有一些常见的颜色，比如绿色，红色，
yellow, purple.
黄色,紫色。
Those have type methods on UIColor.
在UIColor上有类型方法。
Remember, type methods, static methods?
记住，类型方法，静态方法?
They're on the type.
他们的类型。
You don't need an instance of it.
你不需要它的一个实例。
So that's like UIColor.green.
这就像UIColor.green。
But there's also initializers that let you create colors
但也有初始化器让你创建颜色
from RGB, red, green, blue, or HSB, that's hue, saturation,
从RGB，红，绿，蓝，或HSB，这是色相，饱和度，
You can even create a color that's made from a pattern.
你甚至可以创建一个由图案构成的颜色。
brightness.
亮度。
So that when you draw with that color,
当你用这种颜色作画时，
it's drawing in a pattern.
这是一种模式。
Okay, like a really thick line,
像一条粗线，
we'd actually be showing the details of a pattern,
我们实际上是在展示一个模式的细节，
which is kind of fun, using UIImage,
这很有趣，使用UIImage，
which I'll talk about in a little bit.
我会稍微讲一下。
Of course, all UIViews have a background color.
当然，所有的uiview都有一个背景色。
We saw this when we did our buttons in the calculator,
当我们在计算器上做按钮的时候，我们看到了这个，
we made the background color
我们做了背景色
of a lot of our buttons be light gray, and I'm sure in
我们的许多按钮都是浅灰色的，我肯定
the homework assignments you made it other colors.
作业作业你做其他颜色的。
Okay, that's just a var on UIView,
这是UIView上的一个var，
that button inherited from UIView.
这个按钮是从UIView继承的。
And you can set it to any UIColor you want.
你可以把它设置为任何UIColor。
Now, an interesting thing about colors though is that
关于颜色的一个有趣的事情是
they can be transparent, or even semi-transparent, okay?
它们可以是透明的，甚至半透明的?
And they are done, you specify that with alpha.
它们完成了，你用alpha来指定。
How many people here know what alpha
这里有多少人知道阿尔法
is when it comes to graphics?
当涉及到图形的时候?
Okay, so hardly anybody.
好的,所以几乎没有人。
So alpha is just a value between 0 and 1, where 0 means
也就是0和1之间的值，0表示
fully transparent and 1 is fully opaque.
完全透明和1完全不透明。
So if you have a color like a triangle and
如果你有一个三角形的颜色
you fill it with green, then if it's fully opaque,
用绿色填充，如果完全不透明，
you can't see anything behind that triangle.
在那个三角形后面看不到任何东西。
But if it were 50%, 0.5 alpha,
但如果是50% 0。5，
then you'd be able to see the green but
然后你就能看到绿色了
you'd also be able to see the things behind it a little bit.
你也能看到它后面的东西。
50% kinda, okay?
If it was zero, you wouldn't see any
如果它是零，你就不会看到
green because it would be fully transparent.
因为它是完全透明的。
You'd be looking all the way through it, so
你会一直看着它，所以
you wouldn't see any green, okay?
你看不到绿色的，明白吗?
So, all that you can put anywhere in that range, and
你可以把它放到这个范围内
the way you create a transparent color is by taking
你创造一个透明的颜色的方式是通过
a opaque color and saying, withAlphaComponent,
一种不透明的颜色，并说，withAlphaComponent，
whatever alpha you want between 0 and 1.
无论在0到1之间你需要什么。
Okay? And that gives you
好吧?这给你
a transparent or
一个透明的或
semi-transparent version of the color.
半透明的颜色。
And you can draw with that.
你可以画出来。
However, if you draw with transparency in your UIView,
但是，如果你在UIView中使用透明度，
you must set this var on your UIView.
你必须在你的UIView上设置这个var。
This is just a var in UIView to false.
这只是UIView中的一个var。
Okay? Because views assume that
好吧?因为观点认为
they're fully opaque, okay?
他们完全不透明,好吗?
And that's performance enhancement.
性能增强。
It turns out drawing with transparency,
它用透明度绘图，
as you might imagine, takes a little bit of CPU power
您可能会想，需要一点CPU的能力
to figure out which pixels show through and all that.
计算出哪些像素显示了所有这些。
So, by default, it assumes you're drawing fully opaque.
默认情况下，它假设你画的是完全不透明的。
So if you wanna draw with transparency,
如果你想用透明度绘图，
don't forget to set opaque here to false.
别忘了把不透明设置为假。
By the way, you can make your entire view semi-transparent
顺便说一下，你可以让你的整个视图半透明
by setting its alpha.
通过设置其α。
So this is a var, not in color,
这是一个var，不是彩色的，
this is a var in UIView.
这是UIView中的一个var。
You can say, alpha 0.5,
你可以说，
in your entire view will be 50% see-through.
在您的整个视图中将有50%的透视。
And that would work with a button or
这和一个按钮有关
anything because those are just UIViews.
因为这些都是uiview。
Alright?
对吧?
What happens when views overlap and
当视图重叠的时候会发生什么
we have transparency in the views?
我们的观点有透明度吗?
Well, then that subviews that we're talking about,
那么，我们所讨论的子视图，
all the subviews of a view starts to matter in the order.
视图的所有子视图开始在顺序中起作用。
So the first thing in the subview,
所以在子视图中，
subview sub zero, that's all the way in the back.
子视图下标0，在后面。
And then everything else is in the order in front of
然后其他的都在前面的顺序中
it, okay?
它,好吗?
And so, any transparency that's going on is things
所以，任何正在发生的透明度都是事情
stacked up in that order, and you're looking down through
按顺序排列，你向下看
the transparency, all the way up to subview zero,
透明度，一直到subview zero，
so which is in the back, okay?
后面的是哪个?
You can also completely hide a view.
你也可以完全隐藏视图。
This is very similar--almost identical to--saying
这很相似，几乎一样
alpha equals zero.
α= 0。
Which will just make the view not even appear, but
这只会让视图看起来不出现，但是
it will be still in the view hierarchy.
它仍然在视图层次结构中。
It will be still in its superview and
它仍将在它的超级视图中
its subviews will still be subviews of it, but
它的子视图仍然是它的子视图
it all will be completely hidden.
这一切将完全隐藏起来。
And why would you wanna do this?
你为什么要这么做?
Maybe you have some UI where you don't wanna show a button
可能你有一些UI你不想显示一个按钮
until the user has entered some other field or
直到用户输入其他字段或
something like that.
就像这样。
But you wanna make room for the button.
但你要为按钮腾出空间。
You want it to be ready to appear, so
你想让它随时出现
you leave it in the view hierarchy, but hidden.
你把它放在视图层级中，但隐藏了。
Okay? Alright,
好吧?好了,
let's talk about drawing text.
我们来谈谈绘画文本。
How do we draw text?
如何绘制文本?
Well, one way to draw text you already know is UILabel.
一种绘制文本的方法是UILabel。
You could just create a UILabel and make it a subview
你可以创建一个UILabel然后让它成为子视图
of your view and bingo, you got some text in your view.
在你的观点和宾果中，你有一些文本在你的观点。
And now, the only problem with that is,
现在，唯一的问题是，
you're drawing in your draw, your drawRect thing,
你画的是画，画的是drawRect，
you're drawing in there.
你要画。
And you have to make sure you drew, if you're drawing around
如果你画的是画的，你一定要画出来
the text that it all lined up with your subviews.
它都与你的子视图对齐。
So sometimes you wanna draw in drawRect, right?
有时候你想画一个drawRect，对吧?
You want to actually draw in there.
你想要画进去。
And the way you do that is with a class called
这样做的方法是调用一个类
NSAttributedString, okay?
NSAttributedString,好吗?
So NSAttributedString is not a string.
NSAttributedString不是字符串。
It's not related in any way actually to string, and
它与字符串之间没有任何关系，而且
it's not even an NSString which is the old Objective-C
它甚至不是一个NSString，它是旧的objective - c
style string that was indexed by ints where
由ints索引的样式字符串
the Swift's one is indexed by string.index, unfortunately.
Swift的一个被字符串索引。指数,不幸的是。
It's neither of those, it's its own thing.
这两者都不是，这是它自己的事。
Okay?
明白吗?
It's very closely aligned to old NSString,
它与老NSString非常接近，
not as closely aligned to the modern string.
不像现代的弦。
But anyway, what an attributed string is it's a string,
但无论如何，这是一个带属性的字符串它是一个字符串，
you can make it out of a string or an NSString.
你可以用一个字符串或NSString。
And those characters have attributes, colors and
这些字符有属性、颜色和
fonts and things like that, okay?
字体之类的?
And it's very simple,
这是很简单的,
you create one of these strings and
你创建一个字符串
you just send it to message draw at and it will draw
你只需将它发送到消息绘制处，它就会绘制出来
that string at that point at its upper left corner.
这条线在它的左上角。
Then you can even find out the size it's going to need to
然后你甚至可以找到它需要的尺寸
Okay?
明白吗?
draw it by sending the message size to an attributed string.
通过将消息大小发送到一个带属性字符串。
Okay? Now one thing that's
好吧?现在一件事
kind of bummer about attributed string,
关于带属性字符串的bummer，
it's really an old style API,
这是一个老式的API，
var and let don't even work to make it mutable or not.
var和let都不让它可变。
So if you want a mutable attributed string, attributed
如果你想要一个可变的带属性字符串
string where you're gonna change its attributes and
字符串，你要改变它的属性
change its text, you need to have a different class called
改变它的文本，你需要有一个不同的类叫
NSMutableAttributedString.
NSMutableAttributedString。
So things like set attributes, and things of that,
诸如设置属性之类的东西，
don't work on an attributed string.
不要使用带属性字符串。
You have a mutable attributed string.
你有一个可变的带属性字符串。
Now, you can, if you have an attributed string, mutable or
你可以，如果你有一个带属性的字符串，可变的或者
not, you can get back the string that's in it
不，你可以取回它里面的字符串
as a string object using the var string, or
作为使用var字符串的字符串对象
mutable string in a mutable case.
可变字符串在可变情况下。
That's kinda confusing because,
这有点让人困惑,因为
of course, you're used to var and let being how a string is
当然，您已经习惯了var并让它成为一个字符串
mutable or not, but that's how you can get the string back.
可变或不可变，但这就是如何得到字符串的方式。
But let's talk about how you set the attributes.
但是让我们来讨论一下如何设置属性。
So you set the attributes just by passing in this dictionary,
所以你只要通过这个字典设置属性，
called attributes there.
称为属性。
You can either set attributes or add attributes to what's
您可以设置属性或添加属性
already there, and this dictionary, String:Any,
已经有了，这本字典，字符串:Any，
the string is just a key like this is telling you what
这个字符串就是这样一个键，它告诉你什么
the attribute is, like it's a font, or a color, or whatever.
属性是，比如字体，颜色，等等。
And then the Any is,
然后，
it might be a font, it might be a color,
它可能是一种字体，可能是一种颜色，
depends on what the key is, that's why it's an Any there,
这取决于键是什么，这就是为什么它是一个，
because it can be all kinds of things.
因为它可以是各种各样的东西。
And really important to notice here is the range.
这里要注意的是范围。
You see that range?
你看到这个范围吗?
It's not range that I talked to you on Wednesday,
这不是我周三和你们讲的范围，
it's NSRange.
NSRange。
NSRange is an integer indexed range into that string,
NSRange是一个整数索引范围内的字符串，
that attributed string.
带属性字符串。
Old style integer, not string.index.
旧式的整数，而不是string . index。
So this makes for a lot of trouble when you're using
所以当你使用的时候，这就造成了很多麻烦
attributed string in the Swift world.
在Swift的世界里有带属性的字符串。
And my recommendation to you is that you use this method or
我的建议是你使用这个方法
this var rather on String called utf16.
这个var被称为utf16。
utf16 will give you back what's called
utf16将会给你回叫
a String.UTF16View.
String.UTF16View。
That is a collection of the characters, it's not really
那是人物的集合，不是真的
a collection like characters is, but it is a representation
像字符这样的集合是，但它是一个表示
of the string as distinct 16-bit Unicode characters.
字符串作为不同的16位Unicode字符。
Which is much more aligned, in fact I think it's exactly
这更有一致性，事实上我认为它是正确的
aligned, to what NSString does.
对齐，到NSString所做的。
The only problem is, that thing that it gets,
唯一的问题是，
that comes back, is still indexed by String.Index.
它回来了，仍然被索引。
So you have to say what's the startIndex, offset by five,
你得说，startIndex，偏移了5，
that kind of business to move around in there.
那种业务在那里四处流动。
And plus, you can't pass a range of String.Index into
而且，你不能传递一系列字符串。索引
this setAttribute.
这setAttribute。
So you have to kinda convert from String.Index,
所以你必须从str. index转换，
how much you've advanced over,
你已经前进了多少，
to an integer when you make these NSRanges.
当你做这些nsrange时。
So, I'm sorry to say it's difficult.
所以，很抱歉，这很困难。
I'm not gonna actually ask you to do that,
我不会要求你们这样做，
this in the homework.
在作业。
Partially because it, it's kind of a pain in the neck.
部分原因是，这有点像脖子上的疼痛。
And I don't want you to spend your valuable homework
我不想让你把宝贵的家庭作业花光
time working on it.
时间工作。
But just know, if you start using this,
但只要知道，如果你开始使用这个，
that you're gonna have this unfortunate disconnect.
你会有这种不幸的脱节。
And I keep hoping every time iOS comes out,
我一直希望每次iOS出来，
they'll come out with an attributed string, not NS, but
它们会带一个带属性字符串，而不是NS
attributed string, that's matched up with string.
带属性字符串，与字符串匹配。
But they haven't done it yet.
但他们还没有做到。
It's pretty complicated to do, I can imagine, so.
这很复杂，我可以想象。
So what are some of these attributes that you can set?
那么你可以设置哪些属性呢?
So there's things like NSForegroundColorAttributeN-
所以有NSForegroundColorAttributeN——之类的东西
ame, that's how you set the color of the text.
ame，这就是你设置文本颜色的方式。
There's also NSBackgroundColorAttributeName
还有NSBackgroundColorAttributeName
which, fonts have foregrounds and backgrounds, but
字体有前场和背景，但是
don't worry about that too much.
别太担心那件事。
NSStrokeWidth so
NSStrokeWidth所以
you can draw your characters really thick or thin.
你可以把你的角色画得很厚或很薄。
NSFontAttributeName, where you can provide a font.
NSFontAttributeName，你可以在这里提供字体。
And there's about 15 others,
还有15个，
and you can go look in the documentation for all of them.
你可以去看看所有的文档。
But speaking of fonts,
但说到字体,
if you wanna set the font you're gonna draw with,
如果你想设置你要用的字体，
how do you do that?
你是怎么做到的?
Well, fonts are super important in iOS.
字体在iOS中非常重要。
Never underestimate the power of a font in building
永远不要低估字体在建筑中的力量
a cool UI.
一个很酷的用户界面。
Look at all these UIs.
看看这些UIs。
Look at how important the choice of font, size,
看看选择的字体，大小，
position, all that stuff is.
位置，所有的东西都是。
So, how do we get a good font so that our UI will look good?
那么，我们如何得到一个好的字体，这样我们的UI就会看起来很好呢?
Well, we're gonna use this very important static
我们要用这个非常重要的静态
method in UIFont.
在UIFont方法。
So you send this to UIFont, the class,
你把它发送给UIFont，
called preferredFont forTextStyle, okay?
叫preferredFont forTextStyle,好吗?
And so you can specify the text style, which is kind of
你可以指定文本样式，也就是
like, what's the environment you're gonna use this text,
你要使用这个文本的环境是什么，
what kinda text is it?
这是什么文字?
And so there's about eight or so of them.
大约有8个。
But three of them are like a headline.
但其中三个就像一个标题。
This is gonna be a headline.
这将成为头条新闻。
So that's gonna be a bolder font, a little larger maybe.
这是一个更大胆的字体，可能更大一些。
Then body font, that's like, this is the user's data.
然后body字体，这是用户的数据。
So in a Mail message,
所以在邮件中，
this would be the message they're actually typing
这将是他们实际打字的信息
maybe--although it's probably a multi-font.
也许，虽然它可能是一个多字体。
But, and then footnote would just be a small little text,
但是脚注只是一小段文字，
you see, from the bottom?
从底部看?
So I really encourage you when you're using a font,
所以当你使用字体时，我真的很鼓励你，
try to find a text style that will work, okay?
试着找一种可以工作的文本样式?
Because it's gonna be in sync and
因为它是同步的
compatible with all the other apps,
兼容所有其他应用，
because they're using these preferred fonts.
因为他们使用的是这些首选字体。
And also, by the way, if a user goes in Settings and
顺便说一下，如果用户在设置中
sets their font size to be really large,
设置它们的字体大小非常大，
these will automatically get larger, okay?
这些会自动变大?
And, hopefully, if you have your Auto-Layout working,
如果你有自动布局，
everything will expand or contract properly, okay?
所有东西都将被适当地扩展或缩小，明白吗?
There's also system fonts.
还有系统字体。
Don't get confused between the preferred fonts and
不要混淆首选字体和
system fonts.
系统字体。
Preferred fonts are for the user's content.
首选字体是为了用户的内容。
So, that's the difference there.
这就是区别。
Now, most of this stuff, again,
现在，大部分的这些东西，
you're not even gonna set in code.
你甚至不会在代码中设置。
You're gonna set it in Interface Builder in
你要把它设置成接口构建器
the little Inspector window, right?
小督察窗口，对吗?
You're gonna be setting, both preferred fonts and
你要设置，两种首选字体
system fonts can be set there.
系统字体可以设置在那里。
If you wanna use a specific font like Helvetica Bold 13
如果你想使用特定的字体，比如Helvetica Bold 13
point, you can do that.
你可以这么做。
I don't recommend it,
我不推荐它,
but UIFontDescriptor is an important class to know
但UIFontDescriptor是一个重要的类
It's how you describe that font that you want,
这就是你如何描述你想要的字体，
for that.
的。
that special font.
特别的字体。
So, you know, some apps, typography is what they do.
所以，你知道，有些应用程序，排版就是他们所做的。
And so they need to be able to do specific fonts.
所以他们需要能够做特定的字体。
Alright, so that's text.
好了,这就是文本。
How about drawing images?
绘制图像怎么样?
So images, again, you, we have a thing like UILabel.
图像，再一次，你，我们有一个像UILabel的东西。
It's called UIImageView.
它叫做UIImageView。
And you could just make an image be a subview of
你可以让图像成为子视图
your view if you wanted to have an image in there.
你的视图，如果你想在那里有一个图像。
But, again, sometimes you wanna be able to control that
但是，有时候你想要控制它
in your draw, your drawRect.
在你的画里，你的drawRect。
And we do that with the UIImage object, okay?
我们用UIImage对象来做，对吧?
I already showed you actually when I was talking about
我讲的时候已经讲过了
failable initializers how to create a UIImage.
可故障初始化器如何创建一个UIImage。
You just put it in your xcassets file
把它放到xcasset文件中
in Interface Builder.
在界面构建器。
And then you say UIImage named, and it gets it by name.
然后你说UIImage，它的名字。
And if it can't find it, it returns nil.
如果它找不到它，它就返回nil。
So that's the number one way you're gonna get an image into
这就是你要得到图像的第一种方法
your app is put it in xcassets.
你的应用程序被放到了xcasset中。
But there are other ways to do it.
但还有其他方法可以做到这一点。
You can get it from a file, like if you had a .jpg file.
你可以从一个文件中得到它，就像你有一个。jpg文件。
Of course, I haven't shown you how to get files.
当然，我还没有向您展示如何获取文件。
So you don't know how to do that yet.
所以你还不知道该怎么做。
But, you can do it that way.
但是，你可以这样做。
And you can also get it just from raw data, raw jpg data or
你也可以从原始数据，原始jpg数据或者
something that you got over the Internet or from a URL or
你从网上或URL上得到的东西
something, you can do that.
你可以这么做。
You can even do it by drawing with all those path things.
你甚至可以画出所有这些路径。
You can use this UIGraphicsBeginImageContext
您可以使用此UIGraphicsBeginImageContext
for a certain size region.
对于一个特定大小的区域。
And then you can just use UIBezierpath draw or
然后你就可以使用UIBezierpath绘制
get graphics context, whatever, draw in there.
获取图形上下文，无论如何，画在那里。
And then there's an EndImageContext.
然后还有一个EndImageContext。
And it'll capture it and create a little image for you.
它会捕获它并为你创建一个小图像。
So that's another way to do it.
这是另一种方法。
So once you have an image, okay, that you got from any of
一旦你有了一个图像，好的，你从任何一个
these sources, you can just draw it inside your drawRect
这些源，你可以在drawRect中画出来
by saying draw atPoint or draw inRect.
说draw atPoint或draw inRect。
Or actually, I think that's probably drawAt space point,
实际上，我认为这可能是在空间点上的，
not atPoint:.
不是atPoint:。
And drawIn space rect and drawAsPatternIn space rect.
并绘制空间矩形空间矩形空间矩形。
Those do kind of what you would think, right?
这些都是你会想的，对吧?
draw atPoint draws it where that's the upper left hand
画点画出它的左上方
corner, it draws it in its natural size.
角落，它的自然大小。
draw inRect is going to scale it to fit inside
绘制inRect将缩放它以适应内部
the rectangle that you provide.
你提供的矩形。
And drawAsPattern is gonna tile it.
而drawAsPattern会把它贴在上面。
So presumably that's a small image and
假设这是一个小图像
you're drawing a texture or something.
你画的是纹理什么的。
And it's gonna repeat it over and
它会重复一遍
over to fill the rectangle, okay?
填充矩形，明白吗?
I'll fix this slide and repost it.
我来修一下这张幻灯片，然后再贴出来。
Alright, one thing to be careful of with UIView.
有一件事要注意UIView。
When UIView changes size,
当UIView改变大小,
you do not get asked to redraw by default.
默认情况下，您不会被要求重绘。
What it does is, believe it or
信不信由你
not, takes what you've drawn, grabs the pixels, and
不，取你画的，抓取像素，和
stretches them to fit the new bounds.
拉伸它们以适应新的界限。
Okay, now, this is often not what you want.
好吧，这通常不是你想要的。
Often, what you want is, okay, if my bounds change,
通常，你想要的是，好的，如果我的界限变了，
ask me to redraw again in my new bounds, okay?
让我重新画一个新的界限?
So how is this controlled?
那么这是如何控制的呢?
It's controlled via this var in UIView called contentMode.
它是通过在UIView中被称为contentMode的var控制的。
And the contentMode can be things like left, right, top,
contentMode可以是left,right,top，
bottom, topRight, topLeft.
底,topRight topLeft。
That's basically saying, take my bits and
这就是说，取我的位
shove them up into the left corner you know,
把它们推到左边的角落，
one of these spots, center or right.
其中一个位置，中心或右边。
Don't touch, don't do anything with them,
别碰，别跟他们做任何事，
just move them in the new bounds.
把它们移到新的边界。
Well, that's likely to cut off what you've drawn or something
这可能会切断你所画的东西
like that depending on how much the bounds have changed.
这取决于界限的变化有多大。
Like when you rotate, you know,
比如当你旋转时，
the bounds changes quite a bit.
边界变化很大。
There's also the scaling ones.
还有缩放。
And this is the default, scaleToFill.
这是默认的，scaleToFill。
And that says, take my bits and take my new bounds and
这就是说，取我的位，取新的积分限
scale it to fill.
规模来填补。
I can preserve the aspect ratio if I want.
如果我想，我可以保持长宽比。
Although, again,
不过,这一次
that's probably gonna cut something off.
那可能会减少一些东西。
But the real one that you want is redraw.
但你想要的是重画。
If you set your contentMode to be .redraw,
如果你将contentMode设置为。redraw，
then when your bounds change, your draw is gonna be
当边界改变时，你的画就会改变
called--your drawRect, draw with the rect argument.
你的drawRect，用rect参数绘制。
So in your assignment three, you're gonna wanna do this.
在你的作业中，你要做这个。
You can actually do this,
你可以这样做，
you can do it in code by setting that var.
可以通过设置var来在代码中执行。
But you can also do it in Interface Builder, okay?
但你也可以在接口构建器中完成它?
In the Utilities window, in the Inspector preview.
在实用程序窗口中，在Inspector预览中。
Just, I think it's the very top one, contentMode.
我认为这是最重要的，内容模式。
All right, so I'm, I'm gonna be leaving the slides here so
好了，我要离开幻灯片了
I will tell you what's coming up.
我会告诉你接下来会发生什么。
I'm gonna do this demo right now where I'm gonna do
我现在要做这个demo
a custom view, a FaceView, a UIView that draws a face.
一个自定义视图，一个FaceView，一个绘制人脸的UIView。
And then Wednesday, I'm gonna talk about gestures.
周三，我要讲一下手势。
We'll add some gestures to control our face.
我们会添加一些手势来控制我们的脸。
And I'm gonna start talking about multiple MVCs,
我要讲的是多个mvc，
I'll finish up with multiple MVCs next week.
下周我将完成多个mvc。
Your assignment three requires you to do multiple MVCs, so
你的任务三要求你做多个mvc
I'm not going to make it due until a week from next Monday,
我不会把它推迟到下周一，下周一，
because you'll need next Monday's lecture.
因为你需要下星期一的课。
However, I'll probably ship the assignment, the write-up,
不过，我可能会把作业写出来，
on Wednesday, because a big part of that assignment
周三，因为任务的很大一部分
is drawing your own custom view and you'll certainly know
绘制你自己的自定义视图，你肯定知道
everything you need to know to do that right off the bat.
你需要知道的每件事都马上做。
So you can kind of get started on the view, and
你可以从视图开始
then next Monday, you can start doing the multiple MVCs.
下周一，你可以开始做多个mvc。
And you'll still have a full week until the next Monday,
在下周一之前，你们还有整整一周的时间，
to get that done, alright.
为了完成这个任务，好的。
No Friday section this week.
这个星期没有星期五的课。
Okay, so as with most demos in this course,
在本课程的大多数演示中，
I'm going to start from scratch, okay.
我要从头开始。
We're going to do a completely new app.
我们要做一个全新的应用。
No more calculator in here.
这里没有计算器了。
So I could click on here to open my calculator.
我可以点击这里打开计算器。
But instead, I'm gonna go back here to Create a new project.
但是，我要回到这里创建一个新项目。
Okay, it's gonna be Single View Application,
它将是单一视图应用程序，
as I told you they all would be.
就像我告诉你们的那样。
I'm gonna call this one FaceIt, okay.
我将它命名为FaceIt，好的。
And it's gonna start out just drawing a face, but
开始画一张脸，但是
it's gonna do much more eventually.
它最终会做得更多。
And, still no core data or testing stuff yet, so
而且，仍然没有核心数据或测试内容，所以
I'm just gonna do FaceIt here.
我把它放在这里。
It's gonna say where do you want it?
它会说你想要它在哪?
I'm gonna put it in the same place the calculator is,
我把它放在计算器上，
in my Developer.
在我的开发人员。
I'm not gonna be using SCM.
我不会使用SCM。
But of course,
当然,
those of you come who came to Friday section,
你们中来周五的同学，
you'll know how to use that.
你会知道如何使用它。
And here is my new app here.
这是我的新应用。
And I'm also going to do my standard thing,
我还要做标准的事情，
where I'm gonna take these supporting files and
我要在哪里取这些支持文件
move them out of our way.
把它们挪开。
So they don't distract us every time we look at
所以他们不会分散我们的注意力
the Navigator here.
这里的导航器。
Because we don't need those for this demo.
因为我们不需要这些演示。
So just like every other thing we've done, we have a view.
就像我们做的其他事情一样，我们有一个视图。
Here's our story board with our view.
这是我们的故事板。
Oops, not that small.
哦,不是那么小。
And of course, we have our controller.
当然，我们还有控制器。
And I'm gonna delete this out of the controller,
我要把它从控制器中删除，
as usual here.
像往常一样。
And this time, we're going to start right off here
这一次，我们从这里开始
by building a custom UIView, custom UIView subclass.
通过构建自定义的UIView，自定义UIView子类。
Now, the way we do that is the saw way we built
我们这样做的方法是我们建立的
the CalculatorBrain.
的计算器大脑。
We go here, new file, right.
到这里，新建文件。
That's how we add new files to our project.
这就是我们在项目中添加新文件的方式。
But this time, for
但是这一次,
CalculatorBrain we chose Swift File because it, you know,
我们选择Swift文件，因为它，你知道，
it wasn't a UI thing.
它不是UI。
It didn't inherit from any iOS class.
它没有从任何iOS类继承。
But now we're gonna choose Cocoa Touch Class, because
但是现在我们要选择Cocoa Touch类，因为
it's gonna be a subclass of a Cocoa Touch UIKit class.
它是一个Cocoa Touch UIKit类的子类。
So we click that.
我们点击这个。
It says, what do you want it to be a subclass of?
它说，你想让它成为什么?
And we want UIView, but you can see there's other things.
我们想要UIView，但你可以看到其他的东西。
UIViewController, and
ui,
other things that we'll learn later in the quarter.
其他我们在本学期晚些时候会学到的东西。
But this is a subclass of UIView.
但这是UIView的一个子类。
I'm gonna call it FaceView,
我将它命名为FaceView，
because it's a view that draws a face.
因为这是一个吸引人的观点。
Okay, it's a good name.
好吧，这是个好名字。
Alright, so we click here.
好，我们点击这里。
It says, where do you wanna put it?
上面写着，你想把它放在哪里?
We usually wanna be very careful to put it in the same
我们通常要非常小心地把它放进去
place as everything else is.
一切都是一样的。
You don't want it in Supporting Files, and
你不希望它出现在支持文件中
you don't want it at this top level, the project level.
你不希望在这个顶层，项目级别。
You want it inside this folder right here,
你想要它在这个文件夹里，
that has all your stuff in it.
里面有你所有的东西。
So we'll do that.
我们将这样做。
Alright, so here's our FaceView.
这是我们的FaceView。
And you can see right off the bat in FaceView, we get this.
你可以看到在FaceView的bat，我们得到这个。
Which is our draw, okay, the draw with the rect.
这就是我们画的矩形。
Notice that it is commented out.
注意，它被注释掉了。
And that's because for
这是因为
performance reasons, iOS doesn't want to ask views that
由于性能原因，iOS不希望提出这样的观点
don't actually do any drawing, to draw.
不要画，画。
Because it has to keep a backing store for
因为它必须保留一个后备存储器
them, and there's memory stores and all this stuff.
它们，还有存储器和所有这些东西。
So by default this comes commented out.
默认情况下，这个会被注释掉。
But of course, our FaceView is going to draw.
当然，我们的FaceView将会绘制。
It's going to draw a face.
它会画一张脸。
So we're going to un-comment it out.
所以我们要取消注释。
Okay, now we have a FaceView here,
好的，现在我们有了一个FaceView，
it doesn't draw anything.
它不画任何东西。
But I actually wanna briefly go back to our storyboard, and
但我想简单回顾一下我们的故事板
put a FaceView in the storyboard.
在故事板中放置一个FaceView。
And it's really simple but I want to show it to you.
这很简单，但我想展示给你们看。
if we go down to the Object Palette at the bottom here,
如果我们回到底部的对象面板，
And again,
再一次,
where we got our buttons and
我们的按钮在哪
labels, you know I could search here forever.
标签，你知道我可以一直在这里搜索。
There's no FaceView in here.
这里没有FaceView。
But I can go down towards the bottom here, and
但我可以向下到这里，然后
you will see this one.
你会看到这个。
It's actually almost at the very bottom, it's View.
它实际上几乎在底部，这是视图。
See, it represents a rectangular region which draws
看，它代表一个矩形区域
and receives events, as promised.
并按照承诺接收事件。
And so I can pick this guy up and drag him out.
我可以把这个拉出来，把它拖出来。
Okay, and drop him here inside this view controller.
把他放到这个视图控制器里。
And remember that the top level view in this view
记住这个视图的顶层视图
controller is a var called view.
控制器是一个名为view的var。
Okay, a very important var.
这是一个非常重要的变量。
Now, I want this view to fill the whole space.
现在，我想让这个视图填充整个空间。
So I'm actually gonna use the blue dash lines to
我要用蓝色的虚线来表示
make this thing fit the entire space, you see that?
让这个东西适合整个空间，你看到了吗?
Now, well, I also want to do the Ctrl-dragging to
现在，我还要做ctrl -拖动到
the edges that we did in calculator, remember that?
计算器的边，记得吗?
But it's actually kind of hard to do this because I want it
但这很难做到，因为我想要它
all the way to the edges.
一直到边缘。
But since I used the blue lines, I can use a really cool
但是因为我用了蓝色线，我可以用一个很酷的
feature which is down here, this button.
这里的特征，这个按钮。
You see this button in the lower right here?
你看到下面这个按钮了吗?
It says Resolve Auto Layout Issues.
它说解决自动布局问题。
If you click that,
如果你点击,
one of the choices is to Reset to Suggested Constraints.
其中一个选择是重置建议约束。
So that is the system saying, I'll make your constraints for
这就是系统说的，我来给你们做约束
you based on what you did with the blue lines.
你基于你用蓝线做的事情。
So I'm gonna look at your blue lines.
我来看看你的蓝线。
Since I used blue lines all at the edges,
因为我用了蓝色的线，
if I say Reset to Suggested Constraints,
如果重置为建议约束，
it's gonna hook those things to the edges.
它会把这些东西钩到边缘。
Because that's what it looked I wanted.
因为这就是我想要的。
Now I can double-check what it gave me by clicking here on
现在我可以通过点击这里来再次检查它给了我什么
the Size Inspector.
尺寸检查器。
And if you look down towards the bottom of
如果你向下看
the Size Inspector, you can see all your constraints.
尺寸检查器，您可以看到所有的约束条件。
And look at that, perfect Trailing Space to Superview,
看这个，完美的尾随空间，
leading space here.
领先的空间。
Excellent, all exactly what I want.
很好，完全是我想要的。
So here, I've gotten all my Auto-Layout with one click.
在这里，我用一个点击就得到了所有的自动布局。
And that's going to be possible to do quite a bit.
这是可以做很多事情的。
If you use those blue lines and
如果你用蓝色的线
you say Reset to Suggested Constraints,
你说重置为建议约束，
often it'll at least get close.
通常情况下，它至少会接近。
And then you can kinda tweak the ones it didn't get right.
然后你可以稍微调整一下。
Now, the other crucial thing I have to do here
现在，我要做的另一件很重要的事
is that this is currently a UIView.
这是当前的UIView。
If I go over here to this inspector here,
如果我到这里的检查器，
which is the Identity Inspector, you can see that
这是身份检查器，你能看到吗
the class of the selected thing is UIView.
所选东西的类是UIView。
So no matter what I put in my draw,
所以不管我画的是什么，
it would never be called.
它永远不会被调用。
Because this is not a FaceView, it's a UIView.
因为这不是一个FaceView，它是一个UIView。
But I can just click here, and go down and choose FaceView.
但我可以点击这里，然后选择FaceView。
And now I've made this a FaceView.
现在我做了一个FaceView。
all the code I put in my draw is going to draw in here.
我画的所有代码都画在这里。
So now,
现在,
And that's it,
就是这样,
that's all I need to do to put a custom view into my UI.
我需要做的就是将自定义视图放到UI中。
It's very common to want to put a custom view
使用自定义视图是很常见的
in, in the UI.
在UI中。
So that's why it's so simple to do.
这就是为什么它这么简单。
Now all we need to do here is in our FaceView,
现在我们需要做的是在FaceView中，
write the code that draws--draws our face.
写出吸引我们的代码。
So what are we gonna do to draw a face?
那我们要怎么画一张脸呢?
Well, I'm just gonna draw the kind of emoji face, this round
我要画一张表情符号，这一轮
circle for a head, two round eyes, a little smile.
圆一个脑袋，两只圆圆的眼睛，一个小小的微笑。
Okay, a very simple face.
好吧，一张非常简单的脸。
And, let's start by drawing the skull of our face, the,
让我们先画出我们的脸，
kind of the head of this face.
这张脸的头。
And I just start doing that in draw here.
我在这里画一下。
I'm going to use UIBezierPath to do all this.
我将使用UIBezierPath做所有这些。
So I don't actually even need to get the context.
所以我甚至不需要了解上下文。
That UI get graphics, get context, don't even do that.
UI得到图形，得到context，不要这样做。
Just use UIBezierPath automatically
只使用UIBezierPath自动
knows what context you're in.
知道你的背景。
So you don't have to do any of that.
所以你不必做这些。
So what do I need to do though?
那么我需要做些什么呢?
I need to kind of think of how big my face is.
我需要想想我的脸有多大。
I want my face, if I'm in portrait or landscape, I also
我想要我的脸，如果我在肖像或风景，我也
want my face to kind of be the smaller of the two sides,
想让我的脸变得更小，
the height or the width.
高度或宽度。
You know what I mean?
你明白我的意思吗?
Because I always want the face to fully fit in there.
因为我总是想让脸完全融入其中。
So I'm going to let my skullRadius, so that's gonna
所以我要让我的头骨半径，这样就行了
be the radius of my skull, okay, equal the minimum.
我的头骨半径，等于最小值。
And there's this nice min,
这是一个很好的最小值，
you see that min function right there?
你看到这里的min函数了吗?
It's generic-typed like an array.
它的类型像数组一样。
Array of T, so that's the T.
数组T，所以这是T。
It will take any type.
它将采取任何类型。
And it will compare two things, and
它会比较两种情况
return the one that's the lowest.
返回最小的那个。
So I'm going to get the minimum of my bound,
我将得到最小值，
bounds.size.width and my bounds.size.height.
bounds.size。宽度和bounds.size.height。
And then I'm going to divide it by 2, because it's radius,
然后把它除以2，因为它的半径，
not diameter.
没有直径。
So now, see what I'm doing here?
现在，看看我在做什么?
I'm just making it so that my radius of my skull will be
我只是想让我的头骨半径
smaller of the width or height.
较小的宽度或高度。
And then, what about where I want the skull to be?
然后，我想要头骨的位置呢?
Well, I want it to be right in the center.
我想让它在中心位置。
So can I say, let skullCenter equal my center?
我能说，让骷髅中心等于我的中心吗?
Okay, that's a method, can I say that?
好吧，这是一种方法，我能这么说吗?
That's a var, anything wrong with that?
那是一个var，有什么不对吗?
No, I see shaking heads--why not, what's wrong with that?
不，我看到了摇头——为什么不呢，有什么不对吗?
Yeah?
是吗?
He says because it'll start from the top left.
他说，因为它从左上角开始。
Not quite.
不完全是。
Anyone else wanna take a stab at this one?
还有人想试试这个吗?
It's because center, while it is the center of this view,
因为中心，虽然它是这个视图的中心，
it's in the wrong coordinate system.
它在错误的坐标系中。
This center is in my superview's coordinate system
这个中心在我的超级视图的坐标系统中
and I'm in draw.
我在画画。
I need to be in my coordinate system.
我需要在我的坐标系中。
So there's actually two things I can do here.
这里我可以做两件事。
One I could use this cool function in view called
我可以在视图中使用这个很酷的函数
convert which will convert a point
转换成一个点
from one coordinate system to another.
从一个坐标系到另一个坐标系。
So I can go down to this one okay,
我可以把它写下来，
convert CGPoint from view, and
将CGPoint从视图转换为CGPoint
I could convert this point center from my superview.
我可以从我的超视图转换这个点中心。
Okay, so just using center I can convert it.
好，我用中心来转换。
That would be fine, because I've converted it from one
那很好，因为我已经从一个转变了
coordinate system, my superviews, to mine.
坐标系统，我的超视图，到我的。
That's probably a little,
这可能是一点,
someone reading this code is like,
读这段代码的人会说，
hm, why are they doing that?
他们为什么要这么做?
A simpler way to do it is probably just to create
一种更简单的方法可能就是创建
a point, a CGPoint, that is my bounds midX, that's my
一个点，一个CGPoint，这是我的极限，这是我的
middle X, see, that's a rect thing, and my bounds midY.
中间的X，这是一个矩形，我的积分限是midY。
Okay.
好吧。
So I'm just creating the point that is the center,
我只是在创建一个中心，
That makes sense?
这说得通吗?
much more straightforwardly there.
更直接。
All right, so now I have my radius and the center.
现在我有了半径和中心。
Now I need to draw a circle.
现在我需要画一个圆。
So how do I draw a circle?
我怎么画一个圆?
I'm gonna do that with UIBezierPath.
我要用UIBezierPath来做。
So I'm gonna say let path equal a UIBezierPath.
我要让路径等于UIBezierPath。
Now, when we look at the constructors for
现在，当我们看构造函数的时候
UIBezierPath here you can see that we can draw an arc.
UIBezierPath，你可以看到我们可以画一条弧线。
Which is actually what I'm going to use.
这就是我要用到的。
We could draw an oval, which would be cool,
我们可以画一个椭圆，这很酷，
except the argument is a rect, and
除了参数是rect，还有
I have the center and the radius.
我有中心和半径。
So I can't, I don't really want to use oval.
所以我不能，我不想用椭圆。
We could draw a rectangle.
我们可以画一个矩形。
I want a circle, so that's no good.
我想要一个圆，这样不好。
Or a rounded rect.
或一个圆角矩形。
I actually want the circle,
我想要这个圆，
not a rectangle of any kind, okay?
不是任何一个矩形，对吧?
So I'm gonna use this one right here which draws an arc.
我要用这个画一个圆弧。
It just takes a center point and it draws a sweeping arc.
它只需要一个中心点，它就会画出一个圆弧。
And I'm gonna draw this arc all the way around
我要把这个弧画出来
to make a circle, okay?
画一个圆?
So how does that work?
那么它是如何工作的呢?
Here, I'm gonna make some more space.
在这里，我要腾出更多空间。
All right, so it wants to know the center of the arc.
它想知道圆弧的中心。
Well, that's my skull center, right?
那是我的头骨中心，对吧?
It wants to know the radius of the arc, well,
它想知道圆弧的半径，
that's my skullRadius, this easy.
这是我的头骨半径，这很简单。
It wants to know the start angle.
它想知道起始角。
So that's the angle that it's gonna start sweeping.
这就是它开始扫的角度。
I'm gonna choose 0,
我要选择0,
the angle 0 is straight out to your right.
角0是向右的。
Okay, so if you're looking at the screen,
如果你看屏幕，
to the right straight across, that's 0.
向右直，就是0。
And it's in radians,
的弧度,
how many people know what radians are to measure angle?
有多少人知道弧度是用来测量角度的?
Okay most of you.
好吧你们中的大多数。
So radians instead of degrees,
弧度而不是角度，
we measure how much we're going up by radians.
我们测量的是弧度。
Radians go from zero all the way around to two pi.
弧度从0到2。
Around the circle.
在循环。
Start at zero and then it will go around, pi over two,
从0开始，然后它会转到，/ 2，
pi, you know, then pi is 180 degrees and
你知道，然后是180度
then around to two pi is 360 degrees.
然后在2 360度。
So it's in radians, so this end angle has to be in radians
所以它是弧度，所以这个端点是弧度
and I wanna go all the way around.
我想要一直走下去。
So it's 2 times pi.
所以是2乘以。
We know that Double.pi is pi.
我们知道翻倍。π是π。
And then clockwise is whether I'm gonna draw the arc around
然后顺时针是我要画出圆弧
clockwise or the other way.
按顺时针方向，或者用另一种方式。
It doesn't matter because I'm going all the way around to
这并不重要，因为我要一直走下去
get back to the start anyway.
不管怎样，还是回到开始吧。
So I'll just say false.
那么我就说错了。
There you go, counter-clockwise.
就这样,逆时针。
Now, I got a warning here, an error.
现在，我得到一个警告，一个错误。
Let's look at that error.
让我们来看看这个错误。
What does it say, it says the binary operator* (and is
它说的是什么，它说的是二进制运算符*(还有
pointing to this little multiplier right here) cannot
指向这里的这个小乘数)不能
be applied to 'Int' and 'Double'.
被应用于“Int”和“Double”。
Why is it saying that?
为什么这么说?
These arguments to UIBezierPath,
这些论点UIBezierPath,
the floating point arguments like a startAngle and
浮点参数像startAngle和
endAngle, what type do you think it's supposed to be?
endAngle，你认为它应该是什么类型的?
No one?
没有人吗?
I hear it being whispered, yes, CGFloat.
我听到有人小声说，是的，CGFloat。
All drawing has to be CGFloat.
所有的图画都必须是CGFloat。
So is Double.pi, is that a CG float?
所以是两倍。是一个CG浮点数吗?
No, it's a double.
不,这是一个翻倍。
Is two a CGFloat?
两个是CGFloat吗?
Well it might be.
它可能是。
But Swift would have to infer that it's a CGFloat.
但Swift必须推断这是一个CGFloat。
And right now Swift is confused about what that's
现在斯威夫特对这是什么感到困惑
supposed to be because it knows this argument is
应该是因为它知道这个论点
supposed to be a CGFloat, but
应该是CGFloat，但是
the thing you're multiplying it by is a Double.
你要乘以的是2倍。
So Swift doesn't know what to infer here.
所以斯威夫特在这里不知道该推断什么。
Doesn't know whether to refer that to as a Double or
不知道是把它看成是Double还是
a CGFloat.
CGFloat。
So the fix here, luckily, CGFloat has a pi.
因此，幸运的是，CGFloat有一个圆周率。
Just like double does.
就像双。
Now, everybody's happy, because Swift knows how to
现在，每个人都很高兴，因为斯威夫特知道怎么做
interpret this literal as a CGFloat.
将这个文字解释为CGFloat。
And this argument to the endAngle is now a CGFloat.
这个到end角的参数现在是CGFloat。
So now everybody's happy.
现在每个人的快乐。
It's only complained that we don't use path yet.
只是抱怨我们没有使用路径。
Okay?
明白吗?
Excellent, so now we got this arc going all around.
很好，现在我们得到了这个弧。
Let's set something about the path like it's line width for
我们来设置一些路径，比如它的线宽
example, we'll set a nice, fairly thick line,
例如，我们将设置一条很粗的线，
five points wide, that's what that means,
五个点宽，就是这个意思，
five point zero, five points wide.
五点零，五分宽。
And then let's set the color.
然后我们来设置颜色。
So I'm gonna get UIColor, let's say, blue color and
我将得到UIColor，比如说蓝色
we'll say set, and by the way there's setFill and setStroke.
我们会说set，还有setFill和setStroke。
There's also just set.
还有设置。
Set sets both the fill and the stroke.
设置设置填充和笔划。
Here we only need to set the stroke color, but
这里我们只需要设置笔画的颜色，但是
I'll just say set so that you learn about that one.
我把它设为，让你们了解它。
And now I can just say path stroke okay and
现在我可以选择路径描边
it's going to stroke that path.
它将会在这条路径上。
So let's see what this looks like.
看看这是什么样子。
Let's go do iPhone 7 here.
我们来做iPhone 7。
So hopefully this is gonna draw our skull.
希望这能画出我们的头骨。
There we go, a skull.
好了，一个头骨。
Whoo, first time, excellent.
哇,第一次,很好。
Okay, now I don't like the look of that very
好了，现在我不喜欢它的样子了
much because it goes all the way to the edges and
因为它一直延伸到边缘
with a thick line that's actually cut off a little bit.
用一条粗线剪掉一点。
So I want to move that in a little bit so we'll do that.
所以我想稍微移动一下，这样我们就能做到。
Let's rotate and go from portrait to landscape.
让我们旋转，从肖像到风景。
Not good, not good.
不好,不好。
Okay, why is that happening?
为什么会这样呢?
That it's doing that.
它是这样做。
Well, that's that content
这就是内容
mode thing I was talking about, right?
我刚才说的模式，对吧?
It's not calling my draw when it goes to this other
当它到另一个时，它并没有调用我的绘制
bound size right there, so it's just scaling the bits.
这里的束缚大小，所以它只是缩放了比特。
So let's fix both of those things,
我们来解决这两个问题，
let's make it go in a little bit, and let's fix those bits.
让它稍微走一点，我们来固定这些位。
To fix the bits, we're just gonna go back to our
为了解决这些问题，我们就回到我们的问题上
storyboard, and click on our view right here.
故事板，点击这里的视图。
Lets get rid of this.
我们把这个去掉。
Okay, click on our View, and go over to Utilities.
点击我们的视图，然后切换到实用工具。
Inspect this with the Attributes Inspector and look,
用属性检查器检查这个，
the very first one, Content Mode, Scales to Fill.
第一个，内容模式，扩展到填充。
Every time the bounds change it's scales to bits to fill
每次边界改变时，它就变成了位
and we want Redraw.
我们需要重绘。
We could also probably use Center, but
我们也可以用中心，但是
I actually want Redraw because if my bounds got smaller for
实际上我想要重画，因为如果边界变小了
example, I'd wanna draw my face smaller.
比如，我想把我的脸画得小一点。
I wouldn't want to get cut off.
我不想被切断。
Okay, so there's Redraw.
好的,有重绘。
That fixed that one, that was easy to fix.
固定那个，很容易解决。
What about making this thing kinda smaller?
把它变得更小怎么样?
To do that, I'm actually gonna create a var called scale.
为了达到这个目的，我要创建一个var。
And it's a drawing thing so it's a CGFloat.
它是一个绘图的东西，所以它是一个CGFloat。
And I'm going to set it to let's say 0.9 and
我把它设为，0。9，然后
that's going to mean 90%.
这意味着90%
All I'm going to do is take my radius and
我要做的就是取半径
multiply it by that scale.
乘以这个比例。
So by multiplying my radius by 0.9 or
半径乘以0。9
90% it should zoom move it in a little bit right.
Kind of in from the edges by 90%.
从边缘到90%。
So let's see if both those things got fixed.
我们看看这两个东西是否都得到了固定。
So the 90% worked.
所以90%的工作。
Clearly, it's in 90% and the rotation works also.
很明显，它是90%的旋转也可以。
So we're off to a good start here,
我们从这里开始，
things seem to be working just fine.
一切似乎都很顺利。
Alright, so, what's the next thing we wanna do?
好了，接下来我们要做什么呢?
Well, we wanna draw eyes and
我们想画出眼睛
a mouth and things like that, I wanna start thinking
嘴巴之类的东西，我想开始思考
a little bit about my internal architecture.
还有一点关于我的内部架构。
And I'm kinda liking the idea of having some private funcs,
我有点喜欢有一些私人的功能，
like give me the path for the skull.
就像给我头骨的路径。
And have that return a UIBezierPath that
返回一个UIBezierPath
I can then stroke.
然后我可以中风。
And then I'll have the same thing, give me the path for
然后是一样的，给我路径
the eye, give me a path for
眼睛，给我一条路
the mouth, you see what I mean?
嘴巴，你明白我的意思吗?
I'll get all these.
我将得到所有这些。
And so I can just take this code down here
我可以把这段代码写下来
that creates this path for the skull and
这为头骨创造了一条路径
I'll just put it up here and I'll just return this path.
我把它放在这里，然后返回路径。
And then, down here, instead of saying paths.stroke,
然后，在这里，而不是说，中风，
I'll say pathForSkull().stroke().
我会说pathForSkull().stroke()。
Do you see that?
你看到了吗?
Now, another thing is the skullRadius and
另一件事是头骨半径
the skullCenter, I want all the other things like the eyes
骷髅中心，我想要所有其他的东西，比如眼睛
and the mouth to all be relative to that.
所有的嘴都是相对的。
So if I make my skull small I need the eyes to get smaller,
所以如果我让我的头骨变小，我需要眼睛变小，
the mouth to get smaller, everything to move in.
嘴巴变小了，一切都变了。
So I'm gonna use these two guys,
我要用这两个向量，
I'm gonna make them instead of being local variables in draw,
我要把它们变成局部变量，
I'm gonna move them out and make them be private vars.
我要把它们移出来，让它们成为私人的vars。
And in specific they're gonna be private computed vars.
具体来说，它们是私人计算的vars。
So I'm just gonna take what they were before and
所以我要把他们之前的东西拿出来
I'm just gonna return them so that no matter what my
我将返回它们，这样不管我的
bounds is, at any given time, skullRadius,
边界是，在任何给定的时间，
that var--which of course we have to type, so CGFloat--that
这个var，当然我们要输入，CGFloat
skullRadius is always going to match by bounds, okay?
头骨半径总是与边界匹配，对吧?
Because every time I ask for it,
因为每次我要求它，
I'm gonna recompute it using this little function.
我要用这个小函数重新计算它。
And same thing with skullCenter,
和骷髅中心一样，
I'm gonna say private var skullCenter,
我要说的是私有var骷髅中心，
which is also a CGFloat, no this one is a CG point, and
这也是一个CGFloat，没有这个是CG点，还有
it's going to be computed.
它会被计算出来。
Now, one thing you noticed here,
现在，你注意到一件事，
I don't remember if I covered this in the other lecture but
我不记得在另一节课上讲过了
you notice, I'm not saying get here.
你注意到，我不是说到这里来。
See, I'm not putting get and set.
看，我没有把get和set放在一起。
Well, I'm not putting set because you can't set
我不会设置因为你不能设置
the skull center.
头骨中心。
Skull center is always the center of my bounds so
骷髅中心一直是我的底线
I can't set it.
我不能把它。
And then if you have only a get,
如果你只有一个get，
turns out you don't need the get.
结果证明你不需要得到。
Because it's kinda redundant.
因为它是有点多余。
So you get this kinda nicer looking code here.
这里有更好的代码。
So now we have skullRadius and
现在我们有了头骨半径
skullCenter available to all of our methods.
我们所有的方法都可以使用骷髅中心。
And so all our other paths, like path for eye and
所有其他的路径，比如眼睛的路径
all that stuff can use them.
所有这些东西都可以使用。
So let's get started on those.
让我们开始吧。
Let's do path for eye, how about that.
让我们来看看这条路。
So in a private func, pathForEye.
所以在私人的func,pathForEye。
Now actually, probably the path for the eye
实际上，可能是眼睛的路径
is almost the same for the left eye and the right eye.
左眼和右眼几乎一样。
So I'm gonna create a little type here called Eye which
我要在这里创建一个小字体，叫Eye
is just gonna be a little enum.
只是一个小枚举。
And it's gonna just be the left and right eye, so
它只会是左右眼
private enum Eye.
私人enum的眼睛。
Let's see Eye is case left case right, okay.
让我们来看一下眼睛是左向右的，好的。
So I mean it's perfectly fine to use an enum
我的意思是，使用enum是完全可以的
just to represent something simple like this.
只是为了表示一些简单的东西。
You don't have to always be doing methods and
你不必总是做各种方法
associated values.
相关的值。
We don't have any associated values here.
这里没有任何相关的值。
We're just representing it as a way to specify in this API,
我们只是把它表示为在这个API中指定的一种方式，
which eye we want the path, the UIBezierPath, for.
我们想要的是路径，UIBezierPath。
So, by the way, also I wanna have some constants
顺便说一下，我也想要一些常数
that tell me where the eye is relative to the center and
这告诉我眼睛相对于中心的位置
where the mouth is and how big the eyes are.
嘴巴在哪里，眼睛有多大。
So to save a little bit of time here, I'm going to just
为了节省一点时间，我将会
type those in at the bottom here real quick.
把这些东西快速地打在下面。
Look how fast I typed them in.
看看我打得多快。
This is, by the way, how we do
顺便说一下，这是我们的做法
constants in swift we just create a struct and we make
我们在swift中创建了一个struct
static lets on it which are all of our constants and
静态的，它是我们所有的常数
what's really cool about this, one it groups them together.
真正酷的是，它将它们组合在一起。
Like here I have Ratios,
比如这里我有比率，
it's all the ratios between the skull radius and all these
它是颅骨半径和所有这些之间的比值
things I want to do like the eye offset and the mouth.
我想做的事情就像眼睛的偏移和嘴巴。
Also it types them.
他们也类型。
You see these are typed constants.
你可以看到这些是类型常量。
I can put the type in there, because they're just vars,
我可以把类型放到这里，因为它们只是vars，
they're static vars on this struct.
它们是结构上的静态vars。
Okay. We don't have any storage
好吧。我们没有仓库
in this struct.
在这个结构体中。
Doesn't have any methods.
没有任何方法。
It just is only used for constants here.
它只是用于常数。
Now, I'm gonna use these constants down here, and
现在我要用这些常数
I'm gonna use the skull radius and
我要用头骨半径
center up here to calculate the path for the eye.
在这里，计算出眼睛的路径。
So how am I gonna do that?
我要怎么做呢?
First I need the center of the eye.
首先，我需要眼睛的中心。
Now, I'm gonna create a function to calculate
现在，我要创建一个函数来计算
the center of the eye.
眼睛的中心。
But I only need it for pathForEye.
但我只需要它的路径。
So I'm actually gonna put it inside pathForEye.
所以我要把它放在路径前面。
So I'm gonna create a function here, centerOfEye.
我要在这里创建一个函数，centerOfEye。
Just gonna type it in quick here to save some time.
在这里输入，以节省时间。
I'll go through it though.
不过，我还是挺过去的。
And centerOfEye, look how it's inside pathForEye.
而centerOfEye，看看它的内部是怎样的。
And that's perfectly legal, some of you are probably using
这是完全合法的，你们中的一些人可能正在使用
that strategy in your assignment two.
你们作业中的这个策略。
I think I mentioned it in a hint, that you can do it.
我想我已经提过了，你可以做。
And all it does is, it keeps centerOfEye inside here,
它所做的就是，它把中心放在这里，
because it's not needed anywhere else.
因为它在其他任何地方都不需要。
So now, readers of my code don't have to worry about this
所以现在，我的代码的读者不必担心这个
thing being called somewhere else, and
在别的地方叫什么
what it's semantics might be out there.
它的语义可能在那里。
They already know that it's only used in this nice,
他们已经知道它只在这个地方使用，
little space right here, so it's kind of a nice way to
这里的空间很小，这是一种很好的方法
arrange your code to make it a little more readable.
安排你的代码使它更易读。
So how does centerOfEye work?
那么centerOfEye是如何工作的呢?
Well it takes the eye, and
它需要眼睛，而且
it just gets the eye offset by taking the skull radius and
它只是通过头骨半径来得到眼球的偏移
dividing it by one of those constants,
除以其中一个常数，
the ratio between the skull radius to the eye offset,
颅骨半径与眼距的比值，
that's how much it's gonna offset the eye.
这就是它能抵消眼睛的程度。
Now I'm gonna offset the eye the same amount up as I do
现在我要用和我一样的量来抵消眼睛
to the sides.
双方。
So the line between the nose of our face, and
所以我们的脸和鼻子之间的界限
the two eyes is gonna be equilateral triangles, or no,
两眼是等边三角形，
not quite equilaterals.
不等边三角形。
It can be a little wider, but
它可以稍微宽一点，但是
the same distance going up as it is going out to the sides.
当它向两边走的时候，同样的距离。
I'm gonna start with the eyeCenter being in the center.
我先从中心的眼睛开始。
And then,
然后,
I'm starting with the eye in the center of the face, and
我从脸部中心的眼睛开始
then I'm gonna move it up and over.
然后我要把它上下移动。
Okay. So here I'm moving it up.
好吧。我把它向上移动。
Notice that up is minus the eye offset,
注意到向上是减去眼睛偏移量，
because decreasing y is up, increasing y is down.
因为减少y增加，y减小。
And for x, I'm going to add the eye offset or
对于x，我要加上眼睛偏移量
subtract the eye offset,
减去偏移,
depending on whether it's the left eye or the right eye.
取决于是左眼还是右眼。
So for the left eye, I'm going to subtract the eye offset.
对于左眼，我要减去眼睛偏移量。
And for the right eye, I'm going to add the eye offset.
对右眼，我要加上眼睛偏移量。
Okay?
明白吗?
Everyone understand that little
每个人都明白,小
construct right there, I hope.
我希望在那里建造。
Okay and then it's returning the center.
然后它返回中心。
So now I have the center of the eye.
现在我有了眼睛的中心。
So using the center of the eye,
用眼睛的中心，
I can say let the eye radius equal the skull radius
我可以说，让眼睛的半径与头骨的半径相等
divided by the ratio for that one,
除以这个的比，
which is skullRadiusToEyeRadius.
这是skullRadiusToEyeRadius。
Okay, so that's what I'm gonna do.
这就是我要做的。
And I'm gonna let the eyeCenter just
我要让eyeCenter
equal centerOfEye, whichever eye.
等于centerOfEye,哪个眼睛。
The eye that's up here.
眼睛在上面。
So I'm just calling this little function right here.
我把这个函数称为。
And so I have those two things.
所以我有这两样东西。
So I can just create another circle.
我可以创建另一个圆。
So I'm going to let path equal UIBezierPath and
所以我要让path等于UIBezierPath
do that arc again.
再次做弧。
Here the center is the eye center.
这里的中心是眼睛中心。
And the radius is the eye radius.
半径是眼睛的半径。
And the start angle is still zero.
起始角还是0。
Then end angle is still CGFloat.pi* 2, and clockwise,
然后结束角度仍然是CGFloat。π* 2,顺时针,
it doesn't matter.
没关系。
I'll go the other way this time.
这次我用另一种方法。
Okay, so there's my path.
这就是我的路径。
Let's set path.lineWidth equal 5.0 again.
设的道路。线宽= 5.0。
Starting to get tired of typing that.
开始厌倦打字了。
It's probably not a good thing.
这可能不是一件好事。
And then let's return the path.
然后返回路径。
Okay. So that's it.
好吧。这就是它。
So that gets the path for either the left eye or
这就得到了左眼的路径
the right eye.
正确的眼睛。
we'll say pathForEye, the left eye, stroke.
我们会说，pathForEye，左眼，中风。
Okay, pathForEye, the right eye, stroke.
好了，开路，右眼，中风。
Okay, I hope everyone's comfortable with the fact that
好吧，我希望大家都能接受这个事实
I'm calling a method, taking this return value, and
我调用了一个方法，取这个返回值
immediately sending it a message.
立即发送信息。
So, let's see how this went.
让我们看看这是怎么发生的。
Let's see if we got this right.
让我们看看是否正确。
Look at that.
看看这个。
FIrst time.
已经不是第一次了。
It's really going well today.
今天真的很顺利。
Okay, so there's our two lines, they look good.
好的，这就是我们的两条线，它们看起来不错。
You know what would be kind of cool though?
你知道什么会很酷吗?
If we could have open eyes and closed eyes.
如果我们能睁大眼睛，闭上眼睛。
So how could we, how could we have open eyes and
我们怎么能睁大眼睛呢
How about this: let's go up here and just like we had this
这个怎么样，我们到上面这里，就像这样
closed eyes?
闭上眼睛吗?
var scale which by the way notice I left the var public.
var量表，我离开var公共。
Scale, so that people who are using my face view,
规模，所以那些用我的脸的人，
they can control the size of the face.
他们可以控制脸的大小。
I don't mind.
我不介意。
And, I'm also gonna have eyes open, which is going to be
我还会睁开眼睛，这将会是
a bool, which will start out being false.
bool，开始是假的。
And we're just gonna make our pathForEye,
我们只是想让我们的先人，
look at this var, look at the value of this var.
看看这个var，看看这个var的值。
And either have the eyes open or closed.
要么睁大眼睛，要么闭上眼睛。
So, I'm back here in path for eye.
所以，我又回到了眼前。
So, if the eyes are open then we're just gonna do what we
所以，如果眼睛睁开，我们就做我们想做的事
were already doing here, this business.
已经在这里做了，这个生意。
Okay, because that's what we did so far.
这就是我们目前所做的。
But if the eyes are closed,
但如果眼睛闭上，
then I want the path to be different.
然后我希望路径是不同的。
So, watch what I'm gonna do here.
看看我要怎么做。
Let path be a UIBezierPath without a value to start.
让path成为一个没有值开始的UIBezierPath。
Okay, and then I set it here, and I'm gonna set it here, and
然后我在这里设置它，我要在这里设置它
that's allowed.
这是允许的。
In other words Swift is smart enough to know,
换句话说，斯威夫特聪明得足以知道，
you created a let, which can only be initialized once.
您创建了一个let，它只能初始化一次。
But you conditionally initialized it here,
但你有条件地在这里初始化，
because now I'm gonna say path equals.
因为现在我要说路径等于。
And for the closed case I'm just gonna make
对于闭合的情况，我要做
a bezier path that starts out blank.
从空白开始的bezier路径。
And then I'm gonna just move to, line to,
然后我要移动到，
to make a little horizontal line for a closed eye.
为闭眼做一点水平线。
So, I'm gonna say path.move(to: ) to move to
因此，我要写入path。移动(to:)移动到
a point, CGPoint, we use this constructor right here.
一个点，CGPoint，我们在这里使用这个构造函数。
Not that one, let's use, this one, CGFloat.
不是那个，我们用这个，CGFloat。
And the point we're gonna move to we're gonna move to
我们要讲的重点是
the eyeCenter x minus the eyeRadius.
eyeCenter x减去eyeRadius。
So, we're gonna move to the center of the eye and
所以，我们要移动到眼睛的中心
back up with the eye there.
把眼睛放回去。
And we're gonna be at the eyeCenter.y.
我们将在eyeCenter.y。
So, we're gonna right in the eyeCenter and
所以，我们就在眼睛里
we're gonna draw a horizontal line so
我们画一条水平线
we're gonna move to the left side of it.
我们要向左移。
And then we're going to add a line to the right side.
然后我们在右边加一条线。
So, another CGPoint which is this one again.
另一个CGPoint是这个。
And this one is going to be the eyeCenter.x
这个是eyecenterx
plus the eyeRadius.
加上eyeRadius。
And it's still at the eyeCenter, okay?
它还在eyeCenter，对吧?
Make sense?
有意义吗?
Two more parentheses in there.
这里还有两个括号。
Everyone see what I did there?
大家都明白我做了什么吗?
But I just wanna make sure you understood this
但我只是想确保你们明白这一点
thing of let path.
的路径。
You don't have to say equals here as long as this if then
你不必说这里等于这里只要这个
still only initializes it once and doesn't change it.
仍然只初始化一次，不改变它。
Because it's still a valid let.
因为它仍然是一个有效的。
So, let's go take a look at that.
让我们来看看这个。
Okay, eyes closed.
好吧,闭上眼睛。
Excellent, okay?
好的,好吗?
They're closed eyes.
他们闭上眼睛。
We can go back here, set this to true.
我们可以回到这里，把它设为true。
And again, we should get open eyes.
再说一次，我们应该睁大眼睛。
Questions?
问题吗?
So, the question is when do people do a custom
问题是，人们什么时候做一个习惯
view like this when they draw off their own thing?
当他们画出自己的东西时，会这样看吗?
In other words, when they don't use this built in things
换句话说，当他们不使用这些东西的时候
like button and things like that well it depends on
像按钮之类的东西，这取决于
the content that they are providing.
他们提供的内容。
But a lot of times, maybe they are not drawing with arcs and
但很多时候，也许它们不是用弧线画的
circles, maybe they're drawing with images and text okay?
圆圈，也许他们画的是图像和文字?
They're laying how they want down to a level or
他们正在把他们想要的水平降到一个水平
in an orientation that those can do or maybe they're doing
在一个方向上，这些可以做或者可能正在做
text along a curve, which you can do with this for example.
沿着曲线的文本，你可以用它来做例子。
So, it's that kind of thing.
所以，这是一种东西。
You might not see raw drawing like this.
你可能不会看到这样的原始图画。
We're doing raw drawing because it's simple and
我们做的是raw格式，因为它很简单
I'm trying to show you how you do it.
我试着告诉你你是怎么做的。
But there are apps that are drawing
但也有一些应用程序正在绘制
apps where you can take your finger and draw.
应用程序，你可以拿你的手指和画。
They would clearly do this as well right,
他们显然也会这样做，
some of you might do that as your final project.
你们中的一些人可能会做最后的项目。
Okay, so anyway there's our eye.
好了，不管怎样，这就是我们的眼睛。
So, we've got our eyes going, we've got our skull.
所以，我们的眼睛，我们的头骨。
How about our mouth?
我们的嘴呢?
We've gotta get the mouth going so let's go do that.
我们得把嘴弄出来，让我们去做吧。
And we're gonna do the same thing there.
我们会在这里做同样的事情。
I'm gonna have a private func pathForMouth and
我要一个私人的func pathForMouth
it's gonna be a UIBezierPath.
它会是一个UIBezierPath。
So, how I'm going to do the mouth.
所以，我要怎么做嘴巴。
Actually, I'm going to start by drawing the mouth as
实际上，我先画一下嘴巴
a rectangle,
一个矩形,
just to show you where I'm gonna put it on screen.
我要把它放在屏幕上。
And then we'll turn it, we'll use a bezier curve,
然后我们把它转动，我们用贝塞尔曲线，
actually, to make the mouth.
实际上，要做嘴巴。
So, how am I going to do that?
我要怎么做呢?
First, I'm going to calculate
首先，我要计算一下
some things like the width of the mouth, the height of
有些东西，比如嘴的宽度，高度
the mouth, and the offset of the mouth--the offset down
嘴，和嘴的偏移，抵消
from the middle of the face--using more of these
从脸的中间——使用更多的这些
ratios.
比率。
So, I'm just calculating the mouth, width,
我只是在计算嘴的宽度，
height, and offset.
高度,和偏移量。
Now, I'm gonna use that to create the rectangle in which
现在，我要用它来创建矩形
I'm going to put the mouth.
我要把嘴放进嘴里。
Let's do that, let mouthRect equal and so the mouthRect
让我们这样做，让口角相等，然后是漱口
is gotta be offset down by the mouth offset.
必须被嘴部的偏移量抵消。
And it's gonna be the width and height, so let's do that.
它将是宽度和高度，我们来做一下。
So, CGRect we'll use this constructor right here,
那么，CGRect我们将在这里使用这个构造函数，
CGFloat, we'll do the skull's center dot x
CGFloat，我们来做头骨的中间点x
minus the mouth's width, divided by two.
减去嘴的宽度，除以2。
So that's, because we obviously want the mouth
所以这是，因为我们显然想要嘴巴
centered in there, and then for y,
以这里为中心，然后是y，
we'll use the skullCenter.y plus the mouthOffset.
我们将使用skullCenter。y + mouthOffset。
And again it's plus,
再加上,
because plus is down in our drawing system.
因为加号在我们的绘图系统中。
And the width is just the mouthWidth and
宽度就是口宽
the height is the mouthHeight.
高度是嘴巴的高度。
Let me make this a little easier to read like this.
让我把它读起来更简单一些。
Everyone understand what I'm
每个人都明白我
doing there with the mouse rect?
用鼠标在那里做什么?
Let's just draw this rect.
我们把这个矩形画出来。
So, I can say let path equal UIBezierPath.
所以我可以说，让路径等于UIBezierPath。
BezierPath knows how do a rect.
BezierPath知道怎么做rect。
It's this one down here.
就是下面这个。
The rect is our mouthRect and let's just return that path.
rect是我们的漱口，让我们返回路径。
So, now we've got a path for the mouth.
所以，现在我们有了一条通向嘴巴的路。
Let's go down here and
我们到下面这里
stroke it by saying pathForMouth().stroke().
通过说pathForMouth(). stroke()来描它。
Let's see what this looks like.
让我们看看这是什么样子。
Okay, excellent.
好的,太好了。
So, we have a mouth.
我们有一个嘴巴。
Kinda looks like a robot face.
有点像机器人的脸。
We want it to have a nice curve, a smile or a frown.
我们希望它有一个漂亮的曲线，一个微笑或一个皱眉。
So, we gotta start thinking a little bit how we're gonna
所以，我们要开始思考一下我们要怎么做
represent whether this is smiling or frowning.
代表这是微笑还是皱眉。
And so I'm gonna introduce another var, up at the top,
然后我要引入另一个var，在顶部，
here, just like I have it with the eyes are open.
在这里，就像我的眼睛睁开了一样。
I'm gonna have a var which I'm gonna call mouthCurvature and
我要有一个var，我要叫它口器
make it be a Double.
让它变成双。
I'll set it to, let's say 1.0 and
我把它设为，设为1.0
the semantics of this I'm going to have it be that
这个的语义是这样的
1.0 is full smile and minus 1.0 is full frown.
And this is going to be public and this is going to be
这将是公开的，这将是
the public API that someone uses when they want to use my
当人们想要使用我的时候使用的公共API
FaceView to tell me how much this mouth should be smiling.
FaceView告诉我，这张嘴巴应该笑多少。
Okay, the mouth curvature right here.
好的，这里的嘴曲率。
And I've just defined it this way.
我这样定义它。
It's public, I've documented it.
这是公开的，我已经记录下来了。
And so people can set it to whatever they want.
所以人们可以随意设置。
So I'm going to use this now to do it.
现在我要用这个来做。
Now one thing is I've defined it as a double because,
我把它定义为double因为，
you know I'm not actually doing the drawing right now
你知道我现在还没有画
I'm just talking conceptually what curvature is.
我只是从概念上讲曲率是什么。
So, I need to convert this in the some meaningful CGFloat,
因此，我需要把它转换成一些有意义的CGFloat，
and then use that to draw this mouth.
然后用它来画出这张嘴。
So, how am I gonna do that?
我要怎么做呢?
The way I'm gonna do that do that is let's get this back up
我要这样做的是让我们把它备份起来
here and I'll show you, on the rectangle that we have here.
在这里，我将展示给你们，在这个矩形上。
I'm gonna use what's called a Bezier curve,
我用的是Bezier曲线，
how many people know what is Bezier curve is?
有多少人知道Bezier曲线是什么?
Only one person!
只有一个人!
My Gosh, okay so a Bezier curve is just
我的天啊，好吧，贝塞尔曲线就是这样
two end points a line between two end points but
两个端点在两个端点之间有一条直线
there are two other points called control points.
还有另外两个点叫做控制点。
And you can kinda think it as,
你可以这样想，
think of it as the line starts out at the start,
把它看作是开始时的直线，
starts heading for one of the control points.
开始指向一个控制点。
As it gets close, it starts heading for the other one.
当它靠近时，它开始向另一个方向前进。
And as it gets close to that one, it starts heading for
当它接近那个时，它就开始了
the end, okay.
最后,好的。
So, the control points kind of pull on the line and
所以控制点在直线上
give it some curve.
给它一些曲线。
And you can put those control points anywhere you want.
你可以把这些控制点放在任何你想要的地方。
Obviously, we're gonna put ours like this.
很明显，我们要把它放在这里。
So, my start is gonna be right here in the middle of this
我的开始就在这中间
line and my end is gonna be right here.
我的终点在这里。
So we're gonna draw a line across here.
我们在这里画一条线。
And my two control points are going to
我的两个控制点会
be down here somewhere, on both sides of his chin.
在下面的某个地方，在他的下巴两侧。
the line is gonna start here, start down towards this one.
这条线从这里开始，从这里开始。
And so
所以
Whoop. Starting going to
声呐喊。开始要
the other one.
另一个。
Whoop. Come back up here. And make a little smile.
声呐喊。回来这里。做一个小小的微笑。
And if I move my control points up to
如果我移动我的控制点到
the top, then whoop.
顶部,然后大叫。
It'll be a frown.
这将是一个皱眉。
Everyone understand that.
每个人都明白。
So I need four points.
所以我需要4个点。
The start, the end, and the two control points.
开始，结束，和两个控制点。
Let's do those.
让我们来做这些。
The start is easy,
一开始是很容易的,
that's just the middle of the left edge, okay.
这就是左边的中间部分。
So I can say the start is CGPoint.
所以我可以说，开始是CGPoint。
And again we'll do this kind of CGPoint.
再一次，我们来做CGPoint。
And it's going to be the mouth rect, our little mouth rect,
它将会是嘴巴rect，我们的小嘴，
MinX, that's the left edge, the minimum X, and
MinX，这是左边缘，最小X，和
mouthRect.midY, that's halfway up the mouth rect.
mouthRect。米迪，那是一半的嘴巴。
And the end is going to be CGPoint.
最后是CGPoint。
This float.
这个浮动。
And this one's gonna be the mouthrect.maxX and
这个是漱口水。maxX和
mouthrect.midY on the other side.
mouthrect。另一边的米迪。
So the two ends, start and end,
所以这两个端点，开始和结束，
are right in the middle of my mouth rect on either side.
就在我嘴中间的两边。
So now I need those two control points.
现在我需要这两个控制点。
For the control points I need to think of how far down
对于控制点，我需要考虑下有多远
they're going to be.
他们会。
And it depends on the mouth curvature.
这取决于口腔的弯曲度。
The more smile I want, the farther down they need to be.
我想要的微笑越多，他们就越需要。
The more frown I want, the farther up they need to be.
我想要的皱眉越深，他们就越需要。
So I'm gonna create another thing called smileOffset.
我将创建另一个叫做smileOffset的东西。
And this is gonna be a CGFloat, because it's gonna be
这将会是一个CGFloat，因为它会
something that I'm using to do drawing here.
我在这里画的东西。
And I'm gonna make it equal to the mouthCurvature,
我要让它等于口曲率，
which is a double, times the mouth rect.height.
这是一个双，乘以嘴的高度。
So I will move down those control points all the way
所以我将把这些控制点一直移下去
the entire height of a mouth rect if I'm fully smiling.
如果我完全微笑的话，嘴巴的整个高度就会直起。
Now, there's some problems with this line of code.
现在，这一行代码存在一些问题。
One is, if you look at these things right here,
一个是，如果你看这些东西，
it's saying you can't multiply a Double times a Float.
它说的是，你不能把一个浮点数乘以一个浮点数。
This is a float, this is a double.
这是一个浮点数，这是一个double。
So I'm gonna have to convert this to a float
所以我要把它转换成浮点数
by using a constructor for CGFloat.
通过使用CGFloat的构造函数。
Luckily, it has one that takes a double okay.
幸运的是，它有一个双键。
Another thing here is smile offset has to be between,
另一件事是微笑抵消，
you know, one, or sorry,
一个，抱歉，
mouth curvature here has to be between one and minus one.
这里的嘴曲率必须在1到- 1之间。
So I'm gonna enforce that.
所以我要强制执行。
Because I wouldn't want this path curvature to be five, and
因为我不想让路径曲率是5
now he's smiling so
现在他的微笑
big that it's, you know, on the floor literally.
很大，你知道，在地板上。
Jaws on the floor.
大白鲨在地板上。
We don't want that.
我们不希望这样。
So I'm going to use min and max to do that.
所以我要用最小值和最大值来做这个。
I'm gonna say max minus one of min
我要用max - 1的最小值
of the mouth curvature and one.
口曲率和一个。
And that's going to restrict it to be between minus one
这将限制在- 1之间
and one.
和一个。
Everybody got that.
大家都明白了。
I'm just using min and max to do that there.
我只是用最小值和最大值来做。
And notice that it's automatically
注意它是自动的
made these be doubles, which is fine.
这些都是双打，很好。
So the result of min and max is double, and
所以最小值和最大值的结果是两倍
that's being converted to a CGFloat.
它被转换成CGFloat。
That works fine.
工作的很好。
Okay, so now that I have that smile offset,
好的，现在我的微笑被抵消了，
I can say how far down my control points are.
我可以说我的控制点有多远。
So I'm gonna let cp1, which is control point one, it's gonna
我让cp1，也就是control point 1，它会
be smile offset times the mouth rect height down.
微笑抵消了口腔的高度下降。
And I'm gonna make the two control points be
我要让这两个控制点
one third of the way in from the edges of the mouth rect.
三分之一的方式从嘴的边缘。
Does that make sense?
这说得通吗?
We wanted to kinda head down, we wanted to kinda
我们想要低调一点，我们想要
be one-third of the way along from each side.
从两边各占三分之一。
So cp1 is gonna be on the left.
cp1就在左边。
That's gonna be a CGPoint.
那将是一个CGPoint。
And this again.
这一次。
And so this one will be the start.x.
这个是start.x。
Start is where we're starting right here.
从这里开始。
Plus the mouthRect.width divided by three.
加上mouthRect。宽度除以3。
So I'm going a third of the way across.
所以我要走三分之一的路。
And then the y is a start.y plus the smile offset
y是一个开始。y加上微笑抵消
which could be negative if mouth curvature is negative.
如果嘴的曲率是负的，这可能是负的。
Smile offset might be negative, meaning going up.
微笑抵消可能是消极的，意味着上升。
And so, this will be a frown.
所以，这将是一个皱眉。
Or it could be positive and then it will go down.
或者它可以是正的，然后它会下降。
Then cp2 is almost exactly the same so I'll copy and
cp2几乎是一样的，我复制一下
paste it, cp2.
粘贴,cp2。
It's just that here we're gonna go to the end and
只是在这里，我们要走到最后
move back by mouthRect.width.
由mouthRect.width搬回来。
But it's still it's at the same level okay because we
但它还是在相同的水平上，因为我们
want it to come down, go across, and then come back up.
想要它下来，穿过，然后再回来。
So now that we have these control points and
现在我们有了这些控制点
the start and the end, now we can draw that in the path.
开始和结束，现在我们可以把它画在路径上。
So we'll just do go our Bézier path right here.
我们只需要在这里做Bezier路径。
We'll leave the rect in there at first so we can see it.
我们先把rect留在那里，这样我们就能看到它了。
And I'm just gonna tell the path to move to a CGPoint,
我要告诉路径到CGPoint，
which is the start and, actually,
这是开始，实际上，
you don't even need to do that.
你甚至不需要这样做。
You just say, move to the start.
你就说，开始吧。
And then, we're gonna draw a curve, addCurve,
然后我们要画一条曲线，
which adds one of the Bezier curves.
这增加了Bezier曲线的一个。
And we're going to the end.
我们要走到最后。
And the control point is cp1, and the other is cp2.
控制点是cp1，另一个是cp2。
So let's take a look.
让我们来看看。
Alright, excellent, so we have mouth curvature is 1.0,
好了，很好，所以我们的口曲率是1。0，
we've got a nice big old smile.
我们的笑容很灿烂。
Okay, we don't really want this square there anymore,
我们不再需要这个方形了，
rectangle, so we'll get rid of that.
矩形，我们把它去掉。
We can just do that by creating an empty Bezier
我们可以通过创建一个空的Bezier来做到这一点
curve to start.
曲线开始。
Also, we want the path's lineWidth to be 5.0.
另外，我们希望path的lineWidth为5.0。
One nice, even amount.
一个很好的,甚至数量。
And let's go ahead and check some other things.
我们来看看其他的东西。
Let's see if the mouth of minus 0.5.
让我们看看- 0。5的口角。
Let's see if that gives us a slight frown.
让我们看看这是否给了我们轻微的皱眉。
Should give us a slight frown, right.
应该给我们一个小小的皱眉，对吧。
Neat, okay.
整洁,好吧。
Alright, what's the last thing I'm gonna show.
好了，我最后要展示的是什么。
One thing that's a little bit of a pain is
有一件事有点痛苦
every time I wanna check the mouthCurvature,
每次我想检查它的口曲率，
I gotta go run the app.
我得去运行app。
Back, change it, run.
回来,改变它,跑了。
Or every time eyes open, eyes closed.
或者每次眼睛睁开，眼睛闭上。
Back and forth.
来回。
in Interface Builder, okay?
在界面构建器,好吗?
I can see a button
我能看到一个按钮
when I change it's things in Interface Builder.
当我改变它的时候，界面构建器。
And wouldn't it even be cooler if I could have an inspector
如果我能有一个巡查员，我就不会更酷了
in Interface Builder,
在界面构建器,
that would let me inspect these things.
这样我就可以检查这些东西了。
Well, of course we can do that.
当然我们可以这么做。
How do we do that.
怎么做呢。
We go up here, and we just make this IBDesignable, okay.
在上面这里，我们把这个IBDesignable，好的。
If you put IBDesignable in front of a UIView at the top,
如果你把IBDesignable放在顶部的UIView前面，
then when you go over to your storyboard, at the top, you're
然后当你进入故事板，在顶部，你是
gonna see it here, compiling that code, integrating it into
在这里看到它，编译代码，把它整合进去
Interface Builder, and showing it to you.
接口生成器，并显示给您。
Okay now unfortunately we don't have an inspector here
很遗憾，我们这里没有检查员
that allows us to inspect those things.
这让我们可以检查这些东西。
But we can do that as well.
但我们也可以这么做。
Go back to FaceView here.
回到FaceView。
And I'm going to say for
我要说的是
example make the scale IBInspectable.
示例使scale IBInspectable。
Let's make eyesOpen IBInspectable.
让我们把eyesOpen IBInspectable。
Let's make the mouthCurvature IBInspectable.
让我们来做一下这个口曲率IBInspectable。
Let's add a few other things here.
让我们在这里添加一些其他的东西。
Let's make the lineWidth IB inspectable.
让我们做lineWidth IB检查表。
So to do that, we can't have this 5.0 going on over here,
为了做到这一点，我们不能在这里进行这个5.0，
we're gonna have to add a var.
我们要添加一个var。
So we're just gonna add an IBInspectable var.
我们将添加一个IBInspectable var。
Which is gonna be the line width, which is a CGFloat.
这就是线宽，也就是CGFloat。
We'll start it out at 5.0 but we'll be able to change it.
我们从5.0开始，但我们可以改变它。
So now we can go everywhere where we have that 5.0.
现在我们可以到所有的0。5的地方。
We'll just change it to use this var.
我们把它换成var。
We can also do the color.
我们也可以做颜色。
IBInspectable var the color, it's a UI color.
IBInspectable var颜色，它是UI颜色。
Okay, we'll start it out as blue like it is now.
好的，我们将以蓝色开始，就像现在这样。
So where we have view UIColor.blue,
在这里我们可以看到UIColor.blue，
we'll use this var instead.
我们将使用这个var。
Alright, we'll give you a color blue.
我们给你一个蓝色的颜色。
I'm just gonna say color, to set the color.
我要用颜色来设置颜色。
Okay, so basically it's taking all the things in my app and
基本上它把所有的东西都放到了我的app中
just making them not only configurable,
不仅使它们具有可配置性，
as public variables, but also inspectable.
作为公共变量，也是检查表。
So let's go back to our story board and see if this works.
让我们回到我们的故事板看看这个是否可行。
Sure enough, right away, you see up at the top there,
很明显，你在上面看到了，
Face View, the scale, whether the eyes are open, line width,
脸视图，刻度，眼睛是否开放，线宽，
the color, mouth curvature, are now inspectable.
颜色，口弯，现在是检查表。
So let's close the eyes.
让我们闭上眼睛。
Let's have the mouth curvature be 0.5.
让我们的嘴曲率是0。5。
Let's make the color be orange.
让颜色变成橙色。
Let's make the line width be two.
我们把线宽设为2。
Let's make the scale be 0.5.
刻度是0。5。
Make the scale be 0.9 again, whatever.
刻度是0。9。
Now another interesting thing about this is just like if you
另一个有趣的地方是
were inspecting a UIButton here.
在这里检查UIButton。
When you run it's going to use
运行的时候会用到
these settings as the initial settings.
这些设置作为初始设置。
You truly are editing this,
你真的在编辑这个，
just like you would edit anything else,
就像你会编辑其他东西一样，
any other custom view, see it comes up like this.
任何其他自定义视图，都像这样出现。
Got it?
明白了吗?
Now one thing that you have to do when you have
现在有一件事是你必须做的
an IBInspectable is you have to explicitly type you cannot
一个IBInspectable是你必须显式地键入你不能
let Swift infer it.
让迅速推断。
Because while Swift can infer, Interface builder cannot.
因为Swift可以推断，接口生成器不能。
It doesn't have an inference engine there.
它没有推理机。
So always make sure you put the actual type
所以一定要确保你把实际的类型
in all the IBInspectables.
所有的IBInspectables。
Alright, that's it!
好了,这就是它!
what we're gonna do is we're gonna add a model to our MVC.
我们要做的是给MVC添加一个模型。
Next time,
下一次,
And we're gonna start putting some gestures in here.
我们要在这里做一些手势。
And then we'll start talking about multiple MVCs.
然后我们会开始讨论多个mvc。
>> For more, please visit us at stanford.edu.
>> 更多课程详见 stanford.edu